<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006c7089</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006c7089,eee72590-f1ee-4dd8-8cc1-b7b047389840,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Encode Data Inserted into XML Documents</Title>
    <Category>Input and Data Validation</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Technology Independent</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Validate and Encode Data Inserted into XML Documents</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="WikiText">
    <Data><![CDATA[==What to Do==

Validate and encode data inserted into XML documents.

==Why==

Validating and encoding data inserted into XML documents helps prevent XML injection vulnerabilities.

==How==

To validate and encode data inserted into XML documents:

# **Identify XML documents used by the application.** Examine the application design to identify all XML documents and XML document types used by the application.
# **Identify code that handles XML documents.** Review application to find code that uses XML documents.
# **Add data validation methods.** Add methods that validate all the data types stored in XML documents and used by the application.
# **Use validation methods.** Call the data validation methods from the previous step whenever loading XML documents. Validation should be performed before encoding.
# **Add encoding methods.** Add methods that escape XML entities. Unfortunately, there are no stable libraries available for Android to escape XML entities. When writing methods that escape XML entities, consider the following: 
#* Data must first be converted to a uniform character encoding. 
#* XML entities have to be escaped properly. 
#* Code that loads XML documents should be able to restore the original data from the encoded data.
# **Use encoding methods.** Call encoding methods wherever the application processes XML documents. 
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>