<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000003c0cd2</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000003c0cd2,8a8306a5-c6d0-4bf4-887e-e5e070a00e79,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>Data in HTTP Response Headers Is URL-encoded</Title>
    <Category>Encoding</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Data in HTTP Response Headers Is URL-encoded</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Applies To==

* ASP.NET

==What to Check For==

Verify that data in HTTP response headers is URL-encoded.

==Why==

Data in HTTP response headers should be URL-encoded to prevent response splitting vulnerabilities.

==How to Check==

To verify that data in HTTP response headers is URL-encoded:

# **Identify all data included in HTTP response headers.** Search your code for calls to //HttpResponse.AddHeader// to find all code that adds data to HTTP response headers.
# **Verify that data included in HTTP response headers is validated.** Examine code that adds data to response headers. Make sure that any user data is passed through positive validation routines before being included in HTTP response headers.
# **Verify that data included in HTTP response headers is URL-encoded.** Examine code that adds data to response headers. Make sure that any user data is URL-encoded using the //HttpUtility.UrlEncode// method before being included in HTTP response headers.

==How to Fix==

To URL-encode data in HTTP Response headers:

# **Identify all data included in HTTP response headers.** Search your code for calls to //HttpResponse.AddHeader// to find all code that adds data to HTTP response headers.
# **Validate all data included in HTTP response headers.** Use positive validation routines to check all data that gets included in HTTP response headers.
# **URL-encode all data included in HTTP response headers.** Use the //HttpUtility.UrlEncode// method to URL-encode data that gets includes in HTTP response headers.

==Additional Resources==

* For more information about the //HttpResponse.AddHeader// method, see http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/system.web.httpresponse.addheader(v=vs.110).aspx
* For more information about the //HttpUtility.UrlEncode// method, see http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/4fkewx0t.aspx]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>