<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000005d4d08</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000005d4d08,d4ae4f8a-db57-4969-97e7-4834451dac42,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>b6f408c5-6e6e-4bc0-90a5-0bb10becc2ce</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use Server-side Authentication</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>iOS</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use Server-side Authentication</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="WikiText">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Applies To==

* iOS applications that authenticate to a remote server.

==What to Do==

Use server-side authentication.

==Why==

Server-side authentication should be used because client-side authentication is trivial to bypass.

==How==

To use server-side authentication:

# **Define authentication requirements.** Consider the following aspects of authentication control as they pertain to your application:
#* Enforcing password strength requirements.
#* Allowing secure password reset or recovery.
#* Requiring re-authentication for sensitive operations.
#* Using multi-factor authentication.
#* Using simple error messages that don't give away information to the attacker.
#* Using SSL/TLS to secure communications.
#* Throttling repeated authentication attempts.
#* Locking inactive authentication accounts.
# **Implement authentication on the server.** It is important to implement security controls such as authentication on the server, because an attacker could tamper with client-side security controls or disable them altogether. Implement authentication controls that match the requirements defined in the previous step on the server back-end. 
# **Add client-side code that authenticates to the server.** Once authentication is implemented in accordance with the requirements, add client-side code that authenticates to the server. The client-side code will need an interface for managing authentication credentials, network code that communicates with the server using SSL/TLS, a token or some other means to maintain a session state on the server, and possibly secure storage for cached authentication credentials.

==Authentication Guidelines==
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000003cccf2|Change Root Passwords on Jailbroken Devices]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000067c695|Encrypt Authentication Credentials Sent over the Network]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006598ea|Implement a Secure Password Reset Function]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006171ed|Throttle Authentication Attempts]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000005d4d08|Use Server-side Authentication]]

==Authentication Checklists==
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000076b90c|Root Passwords Have Been Changed on Jailbroken Devices]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000004ce47f|Authentication Credentials Sent over the Network Are Encrypted]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006b19fc|A Secure Password Reset Function Is Implemented]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000816c4a|Authentication Attempts Are Throttled]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000002a3f4d|Authentication Is Implemented on the Server-side]]

==Additional Resources==

* For more information about authentication requirements, please see https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Authentication_Cheat_Sheet]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>