<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1031f467-7c2e-46fe-8261-7851371fa672</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006e3400,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>7d2d0571-e542-45cd-9335-d7a0556c2bea</Library_Id>
    <Title>The User Is Asked for Permission Before Geopositioning</Title>
    <Category>Privacy and Trust</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>HTML5</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>The User Is Asked for Permission Before Geopositioning</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Applies To==

* HTML5

==What to Check For==

Verify that user permission is required before using geopositioning.

==Why==

Ask the user for permission before using geopositioning functionality to avoid privacy issues.

==How to Check==

To verify that user permission is required to use geopositioning functions:

# **Identify if the application uses geopositioning.** Search the application code for the use of getCurrentPosition and watchPosition functions to identify whether the application uses geopositioning. Create a spreadsheet to list each piece of code that calls these functions.
# **Verify that the user is asked for permission to use geopositioning.** Log in to the application and access the functions that require geopositioning. Take note of whether the application asks you for permission before using geopositioning.

==How to Fix==

To ask the user for permission before calling geopositioning functions:

# **Determine if the application uses geopositioning.** Search the application code for use of the getCurrentPosition and watchPosition functions to determine whether the application uses geopositioning. Create a spreadsheet to list each piece of code that calls these functions.
# **Write a message asking the user for permission to use geopositioning.** If the application uses geopositioning functions, write a polite message explaining to the user the benefits of using them, and asking for permission to use these functions. 
# **Ask the user for permission to use geopositioning.** For each piece of code that uses getCurrentPosition and/or watchPosition functions, add code that displays the message from the previous step. Add a conditional statement that only executes code that uses getCurrentPosition and/or watchPosition functions if the user has granted permission to do so.

==Privacy and Trust Guidelines==

* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000001de66c|Ask User Permission Before Using Geopositioning]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000364213|Ask User Permission Before Sending a Manifest]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000003b92c3|Tell Users to Clear the Cache after Browsing Through Untrusted Networks]]

==Privacy and Trust Checklist Items==

* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000006e3400|The User Is Asked for Permission Before Geopositioning]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000085555d|The User Is Asked for Permission Before Sending a Manifest]]
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000003087b2|Users Are Told to Clear the Cache After Browsing Through Untrusted Networks]]

]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>