<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1725353421" Content_Hash="2013923214">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>af1f5769-6836-41d1-ba11-14e739e16a13</Id>
    <Library_Id>47a10a30-15ad-4cfd-bf82-00e9bb2037f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Information Storage Media Is Physically Secure</Title>
    <Category>Physical Security</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Information Storage Media Is Physically Secure</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 9.6</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Information storage media, including paper, should be physically secured.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Information storage media, which contains cardholder data, should be physically secured to ensure that a thief cannot steal it. This applies to paper hard copies as well as to digital media.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Examine the security procedures to verify that the facility is sufficiently secure physically. Examine the following potential sources of information leaks to make sure they are physically secure and verify that only authorized personnel have access to these
 potential sources of information leaks:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Computers </li>
    <li>Removable storage media </li>
    <li>Networking and communications hardware </li>
    <li>Network jacks</li>
    <li>Paper receipts </li>
    <li>Paper reports </li>
    <li>Faxes </li>
    <li>Copier cache memory </li>
    <li>Any other places or devices where cardholder information may be stored, written, or transmitted</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Different companies opt for different security measures. Generally speaking, physical security involves security guards, surveillance operators, surveillance equipment, physical barriers, alarms, locks, and card-based access controls. If your company has
 lax physical security, consider adding layers of the above-mentioned security measures until physical security is considered satisfactory.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>