<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1975707433" Content_Hash="-1032826733">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>c57eaf7a-f02e-4172-8221-38fb47dbf402</Id>
    <Library_Id>47a10a30-15ad-4cfd-bf82-00e9bb2037f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Keep Anti-Virus Logs</Title>
    <Category>Auditing and Logging</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Keep Anti-Virus Logs</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 5.2.d </li>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 10.7</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Keep logs generated by anti-virus software for a year or more.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Keeping anti-virus logs helps investigate security incidents. One of the biggest questions that may be answered by reviewing anti-virus logs is whether the compromise was due to a non-specific automated threat or due to a targeted attack.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Perform the following actions to assure that the anti-virus keeps logs in compliance with PCI DSS:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Enable logging.</strong> Locate the anti-virus administration interface. Some anti-virus packages have a control panel on the systems where they are deployed and some anti-virus suites offer a centralized control panel. The number of options offered
 by the anti-virus interface is usually small enough that a person with an IT background can figure out what all of them are and how to use them. The administration interface should offer an option to maintain anti-virus logs. If this option is not available,
 please consider installing and configuring a different anti-virus. </p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Configure the anti-virus to retain logs for a year or more.</strong> If the software does not support storing logs for a year, configure it to store logs for at least three months. If the software does not allow storing the logs for at least three
 months, please consider installing and configuring a different anti-virus. If the anti-virus supports storing logs for at least three months, but not for a year, implement backup procedures to keep the anti-virus logs for at least a year.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Integrate the anti-virus with the centralized log server. </strong>Ideally, the anti-virus should be integrated with the centralized log server, and the log server should keep the logs for at least a year. Ask the anti-virus vendor about integration
 with your log server. Configure the anti-virus to send logs to the centralized log server by following the vendor's instructions. Consider using a different anti-virus if yours is not compatible with your log server.</p>
    </li>
  </ol>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>