<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1625864106" Content_Hash="-292299090">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>099fe70b-15a6-45e4-84a8-95d9d98e9581</Id>
    <Id_History>099fe70b-15a6-45e4-84a8-95d9d98e9581,c818f95a-6c9e-4336-a0ac-5a134b34c943,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Send Logs to a Remote Server</Title>
    <Category>Auditing and Logging</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>All</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Send Logs to a Remote Server</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>C++</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Send logs to a centralized log server.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Sending logs to a centralized log server makes it simpler to secure and monitor logs on a network with multiple log-generating devices.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Use the following steps to implement sending logs to a centralized log server:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Design the logging subsystem.</strong> Design and implement a class or library specifically for logging. When designing the logging subsystem, consider sending logs to a remote log server. Consider the following factors when designing the logging subsystem:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Log throttling<li>Logging important event details<li>Logging important security operations<li>Logging important business operations<li>Monitoring the use of privileged accounts<li>Logging authentication events<li>Avoiding including sensitive information in logs<li>Logging unusual activity</li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li>
      </ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Choose a protocol for communicating with the log server.</strong> The Internet standard for sending logs remotely is syslogd (RFC 5424). It is recommended to use syslogd, because it is supported by most centralized logging solutions, such as commercial IDS and IPS systems.</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Implement the logging subsystem.</strong> Write code that generates log entries and sends them to a remote log server via your protocol of choice.</p>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For more information about the syslog protocol, please see <a href="http://tools.ietf.org/rfc/rfc5424.txt">http://tools.ietf.org/rfc/rfc5424.txt</a></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/7af4efea-59f5-468a-b5a1-c423cd29744a">Centralize Logging</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>