<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-261388651" Content_Hash="1546712161">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1e240c0b-5d16-4191-b842-579809433eff</Id>
    <Id_History>1e240c0b-5d16-4191-b842-579809433eff,2319a68c-9e0c-4c3b-8cbd-d54a94cc8284,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>.NET Encode Untrusted Data in Output</Title>
    <Category>Encoding</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET</Technology>
    <Type>Code Example</Type>
    <DirectLink>Encode Echoed Input</DirectLink>
    <Tag>ASP.NET,ASP.NET 4.0,ASP</Tag>
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="markdown">
    <Data><![CDATA[## Applies To ##

* ASP.NET 4.0 and above.


## Summary ##

Encode special characters in user input displayed on pages based on context that this output is presented in. The most common contexts are HTML, URLs and JavaScript. Occasionally, user input is presented as a part of CSS. Special characters in user data presented in XML documents also need to be encoded, but for that it is best to use parameterized APIs that build XML documents, rather than concatenating encoded user data into XML documents.


## Problem Example ##

ASP.NET platforms starting with .NET 4.0 include a feature called request validation, which effectively mitigates the bulk of reflected XSS vulnerabilities, making it difficult to come up with an example that does not appear unnecessarily contrived. That does not mean that encoding should not be used - untrusted data should still be encoded as a defense in depth measure and to prevent persistent XSS vulnerabilities.


## Solution Example ##

Include the AntiXSS namespace:

	using System.Web.Security.AntiXss;

Create an encode object and use it to encode untrusted data before rendering it to the client:

	AntiXssEncoder encoder = new AntiXssEncoder();
	String safeText = AntiXssEncoder.HtmlEncode(Request.Form["text"],false);
	Literal1.Text = safeText;

The HtmlEncode function encodes for the HTML context. The other supported contexts are: XML, CSS and URL. Use the corresponding method to encode for these contexts. For example, to encode for the URL context:

	AntiXssEncoder encoder = new AntiXssEncoder();
	String safeText = AntiXssEncoder.UrlEncode(untrustedData,false);

## Guideline ##

* [Encode Untrusted Data in Output](9b0ef1a5-c143-4e64-81cc-9e02ccbd9fbd)

---
Adapted from Microsoft patterns & practices guidance. ]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>