<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1892114610" Content_Hash="-2113847415">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>39d503df-f7b8-4db0-8310-318a7d13dfc2</Id>
    <Id_History>39d503df-f7b8-4db0-8310-318a7d13dfc2,7ae74f71-4eb0-4255-b5db-5cf07bf4d015,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use IIS to Host Your WCF Service Wherever Possible</Title>
    <Category>Hardening</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>WCF</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use IIS to Host Your WCF Service Wherever Possible</DirectLink>
    <Tag>WCF 3.5</Tag>
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Jason Taylor, Prashant Bansode, Carlos Farre, Madhu Sundararajan, Rob Boucher, Steve Gregersen</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Microsoft&#174; Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) 3.5 <li>Microsoft Visual Studio&#174; 2008</li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Use Internet Information Services (IIS) to host your WCF service wherever possible. </p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>IIS hosting provides a large number of features for efficient service management and scalability.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>IIS 6.0 only supports bindings over HTTP, so if you need to use TCP, MSMQ, or named pipes, you should host in a Windows service instead. IIS 7.0 supports all of the commonly used transport protocols such as HTTP, TCP, MSMQ, and named pipes. By using IIS as your WCF service host, you can take full advantage of IIS features such as process recycling, idle shutdown, process health monitoring, and message-based activation.</p>
  <p>Perform the following steps when you want to develop and deploy a WCF service that is hosted in IIS:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>Ensure that IIS, WCF, and the WCF activation component are correctly installed and registered.</li>
    <li>Create a new IIS application, or reuse an existing ASP.NET application.</li>
    <li>Create a .svc file for the WCF service.</li>
    <li>Deploy the service implementation to the IIS application.</li>
    <li>Configure the WCF service.<br /></li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For&nbsp; more information, see &#8220;How to: Host a WCF Service in IIS&#8221; at <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733766.aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733766.aspx</a></li>
  </ul>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns & practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>