<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1727165459" Content_Hash="1353886563">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>46d5c420-fe2e-448a-9946-a918d77ac847</Id>
    <Id_History>6d014bba-3a1b-4795-8ef1-39fe30f123fe,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>If You Use SQL Authentication, Use Strong Passwords</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ADO.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>If You Use SQL Authentication, Use Strong Passwords</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Blaine Wastell, Prashant Bansode, Chaitanya Bijwe</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>ADO.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>If you use SQL Server authentication, make sure that you use a least-privileged account with a strong password </p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Using strong passwords decreases the likelihood that an attacker is able to gain access to an account by guessing the&amp;nbsp;password.&amp;nbsp;Failing to use sufficiently strong passwords might make it possible for an attacker to succesfully brute-force crack a password without resorting to millions of attempts.&amp;nbsp;</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>This guideline is applicable&amp;nbsp;whenever SQL authentication is used. Never use weak passwords for SQL authentication.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Here are the steps that should be followed to create a strong password:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <strong>DO </strong>use a password with mixed-case letters. Use uppercase letters throughout the password. </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> just capitalize the first letter, but add uppercase letters throughout the password.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use a network login ID in any form (reversed, capitalized, or doubled as a password). </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO</strong> use a password that contains alphanumeric characters and include punctuation, such as ! and $.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use your first, middle or last name or anyone else’s in any form. Do not use initials or any nicknames.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use a word contained in English or foreign dictionaries, spelling lists, or other word lists and abbreviations.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO</strong> use at least seven characters.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use other information easily obtainable. This includes pet names, license plate numbers, telephone numbers, identification numbers, the brand of your automobile, the name of the street you live on, and so on. Such passwords are very easily guessed by someone who knows the user.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO</strong> use a seemingly random selection of letters and numbers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use a password of all numbers, or a password composed of alphabet characters. Mix numbers and letters.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO </strong>use a password that can be typed quickly, without having to look at the keyboard. This makes it harder for someone to steal&amp;nbsp;a password by looking at&amp;nbsp;the keyboard (also known as "shoulder surfing").&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use dates e.g., September, SEPT1999 or any combination thereof.&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO</strong> change passwords regularly. The more critical an account to network integrity (such as root on a Unix host or Administrator on Windows NT), the more frequently the password should be changed. This change stops someone who has already compromised an account from continued access. </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use keyboard sequences, e.g., qwerty.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use a sample password, no matter how good, from a book that discusses information and computer security.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> use any of the above things spelled backwards, or in caps, or otherwise disguised.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>DO NOT</strong> reveal a password to anyone, as this automatically&amp;nbsp;invalidates it's strength.&amp;nbsp; </li>
  </ol>
  <p>
    <strong>Note</strong>&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;In SQL Server 2005, you can enable an account option to require strong passwords and the server will check passwords against the server operating system password policy.</p>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>