<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-461534875" Content_Hash="243983972">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>47000786-c65f-40a2-8c3e-911b247fe88f</Id>
    <Id_History>49a8b560-aa43-4703-80fe-b04621aac805,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use Multiple Gatekeepers</Title>
    <Category>Authorization</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>Web Application</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use Multiple Gatekeepers</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Michael Dunner, Srinath Vasireddy, Ray Escamilla and Anandha Murukan</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <div>Web Application</div>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Make sure that your design does not rely on a single gatekeeper to enforce access control. Consider what happens if this gatekeeper fails or if an attack manages to bypass it. </p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>If your design rely on a single gatekeeper, a user can gain unauthorized access,&amp;nbsp;if it is bypassed or is improperly configured.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>This is an important guideline and should be followed all the time.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>On the server side, you can use IP Security Protocol (IPSec) policies to provide host restrictions to restrict server-to-server communication. For example, an IPSec policy might restrict any host apart from a nominated Web server from connecting to a database server. IIS provides Web permissions and Internet Protocol/ Domain Name System (IP/DNS) restrictions. IIS Web permissions apply to all resources requested over HTTP regardless of the user. They do not provide protection if an attacker manages to log on to the server. For this, NTFS permissions allow you to specify per user access control lists. Finally, ASP.NET provides URL authorization and File authorization together with principal permission demands. By combining these gatekeepers you can develop an effective authorization strategy.</p>
  <br />
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>