<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1528374313" Content_Hash="-1238316362">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>632a1ca4-eb02-41b9-beec-b53cee1016dd</Id>
    <Id_History>c501eda5-513c-42f4-acff-b405b50ffad3,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>92718d53-36b2-47bc-b6f5-e60994385f46</Library_Id>
    <Title>If You Turn Off Mutual Authentication, Be Aware of Service Spoofing</Title>
    <Category>Networking</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>WCF 3.5</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>If You Turn Off Mutual Authentication, Be Aware of Service Spoofing</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Jason Taylor, Prashant Bansode, Carlos Farre, Madhu Sundararajan, Rob Boucher, Steve Gregersen</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Microsoft® Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) 3.5 
<li>Microsoft Visual Studio® 2008</li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>If you turn&amp;nbsp;off Mutual Authentication, be aware of service spoofing.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>This allows&amp;nbsp;the calls to your service may be diverted to a malicious service through DNS poisoning or a man in the middle attack.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Be aware that your service may be spoofed by a malicious attacker if you are running your service in a scenario in which mutual authentication has been turned off. Without mutual authentication, calls to your service may be diverted to a malicious service through DNS poisoning or a man in the middle attack.</p>
  <p>The follow scenarios will result in mutual authentication being turned off:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>If you turn off message and transport security on your binding
<li>If you use basicHttpBinding which has message and transport security turned off by default
<li>If you use NTLM authentication</li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For more information on authentication, see “Authentication” at <a href="http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733082.aspx">http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733082.aspx</a><li>For more information on choosing a transport, see “Choosing a Transport” at <a href="http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733769.aspx">http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733769.aspx</a></li></li>
  </ul>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>