<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1988235094" Content_Hash="1856609869">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>78ec915f-8f57-41af-937c-a029c9bb6133</Id>
    <Id_History>6233d3e9-e63e-4e19-9b16-8c54a7b8a4df,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>Avoid Universal Data Link (UDL) Files Where Possible</Title>
    <Category>Configuration</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ADO.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Avoid Universal Data Link (UDL) Files Where Possible</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Blaine Wastell, Prashant Bansode, Chaitanya Bijwe</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>ADO.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>You should avoid supplying connection information for an <b>OleDbConnection</b> in a Universal Data Link (UDL) file. </p>
  <p>If you must use UDL files, restrict access to them by configuring an access control list (ACL) that restricts access to the account under which your application runs.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>UDL files are not encrypted and expose connection string information in clear text. Because a UDL file is an external file-based resource to your application, it cannot be secured by using the .NET Framework.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>You should avoid supplying connection information for an <b>OleDbConnection</b> in a Universal Data Link (UDL) file, wherever possible.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>If you must use UDL files, restrict access to them by configuring an access control list (ACL) that restricts access to the account under which your application runs.. </p>
  <ul>
    <li>Assign appropriate permissions to the UDL files. <ul><li>Only administrators should have full access to the UDL files.&amp;nbsp; </li><li>The Account under which your application runs should have read only access to the UDL files.&amp;nbsp; </li></ul></li>
    <li>Minimize the number of individuals who can manipulate or access&amp;nbsp;the UDL files.&amp;nbsp; Authorize access only to highly trusted accounts such as administrators. </li>
  </ul>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>