<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="717738808" Content_Hash="-924491194">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>794753b3-c844-4b51-8317-e3792ff906fd</Id>
    <Id_History>433d836f-a652-4d76-8c6e-4c951faf3696,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use Code Access Security to Isolate Applications</Title>
    <Category>Code Access Security</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use Code Access Security to Isolate Applications</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Blaine Wastell, Prashant Bansode, Andy Wigley, Kishore Gopalan</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>ASP.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Ensure that applications cannot read each other's data or interfere with one another in any way when&amp;nbsp;the deployment&amp;nbsp;environment dictates that appications cannot assume implicit trust with&amp;nbsp;each other.&amp;nbsp;Place restrictions on the types of shared system resources that the applications can access.&amp;nbsp;</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Isolation strengthens resiliency because it makes each application separate and independent. In the event that an application is compromised, isolated apps are less prone to cascading failure (i.e., security vulnerabilities that affect one application will be isolated from the other applications.) </p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>Service providers that need to host multiple applications or anyone responsible for running multiple applications in a shared environment should be isolating their software components. Whenever multiple applications reside on a shared hosting environment, this is appropriate. This is not appropriate&amp;nbsp;when a single application resides on a server and does not share any resources with other applications or services.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>To use code access security, follow these ordered steps:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <strong>Identify the permissions your application needs.</strong> Identify the precise set of code access security permissions that your application requires. You can do this by manually reviewing your code, or by using the Permissions Calculator (permcalc.exe). </li>
    <li>
      <strong>Choose an appropriate trust level.</strong> Try to evaluate whether the permissions required for your application match those provided by any of the standard trust levels. </li>
    <li>
      <strong>Configure your ASP.NET application.</strong> You can configure your&amp;nbsp;ASP.NET application to use a standard level either in your application's Web.config file or in the machine-level Web.config file. Machine level configuration affects all the ASP.NET Web Applications and Web services&amp;nbsp;hosted&amp;nbsp;on that server. Application-level configuration affects only a specific application.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; </li>
    <li>
      <strong>Optionally create a custom trust level.</strong> You may require a custom trust level if none of the predefined trust levels provide the exact set of permissions that your application needs to run. For example, you may find that your application needs more permissions than Medium trust provides but fewer permissions than High trust provides. </li>
  </ol>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>