<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1693635300" Content_Hash="555350933">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>7ba35768-fbd3-4b9c-94c1-17a2dc936471</Id>
    <Id_History>7ba35768-fbd3-4b9c-94c1-17a2dc936471,d4146065-45b1-4fb7-a87c-18674e3e64c9,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>[JUNK] Secure Log Files</Title>
    <Category>Auditing and Logging</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>Web Application</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Secure Log Files</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Michael Dunner, Srinath Vasireddy, Ray Escamilla and Anandha Murukan</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Web Application</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Secure log files using Windows ACLs and restrict access to the log files.&amp;nbsp; Minimize the number of individuals who can manipulate the log files.&amp;nbsp; Authorize access only to highly trusted accounts such as administrators.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Securing log files makes it more difficult for attackers to tamper with log files to cover their tracks.&amp;nbsp; </p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>When logging information, secure the log files with restricted access so that only highly trusted accounts such as administrators can access it.</p>
  <span>
  </span>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Check whether your application design factors in how log files are backed up, archived, and analyzed. Log files should be archived regularly to ensure that they do not fill up or start to cycle, and they should be regularly analyzed to detect signs of intrusion. Also ensure that any accounts used to perform the backup are least privileged and that you secure any additional communication channels exposed purely for the purpose of the backup.</p>
  <br />
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>