<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1517954688" Content_Hash="522561656">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>ac9a5556-8dde-4558-a0eb-21270bcf0077</Id>
    <Id_History>d04f4b77-2054-45e9-9e24-ca5bc8317f5a,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Review the Firewall Configuration</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Test</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Review the Firewall Configuration</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.6<li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.6.a<li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.6.b</li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Review the firewall configuration&amp;nbsp;at least every six months&amp;nbsp;to make sure that it is secure and matches the business needs.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>The firewall configuration should be secure by design; the review process is helpful to make sure that is the case. The business needs of a company may change over time, resulting in different network services being used or a different network configuration, either of which may require a change in the firewall policy. A periodic review process helps ensure that the changes to the firewall policy have been made successfully.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>PCI DSS requires that the firewall configuration be reviewed at least every six months.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Perform the following actions to review the firewall configuration in compliance with PCI DSS:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p />
      <p>
        <strong>Identify the firewall locations. </strong>Verify that there are firewalls&amp;nbsp;at every Internet connection. Verify that there are firewalls between the cardholder data environment and any DMZs. Verify that there are firewalls between the internal network and any wireless networks. Record any changes that need to be made or state that the firewall locations have been reviewed and don't require any changes. </p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Review the firewall rule-set. </strong>Identify the services necessary for business operations. Identify the ports and protocols used by these services. Make a list of these services and their settings. Compare this list to the one included in the network documentation.&amp;nbsp;Check that there is a rule for each port and protocol that is&amp;nbsp;required by each necessary service. Make sure that there is a default "deny all" rule or "deny after allow" setting. Verify that there is a rule that&amp;nbsp;blocks all IP address ranges that are used on the internal networks inbound from the Internet facing interface. Record any changes that need to be made or state that the firewall rule-set has been reviewed and doesn't require any changes.</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Check if dynamic packet filtering is enabled. </strong>Verify that "dynamic packet filtering" is enabled. Record any changes that need to be made or state that "dynamic packet filtering" has been verified and is enabled.</p>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Install and configure personal firewalls. </strong>Verify that all mobile and/or employee-owned computers that&amp;nbsp;are used to access the company network have personal firewalls installed, configured, and that the users cannot disable the personal firewalls or change their settings. Record any changes that need to be made or state that the personal firewalls have been checked and don't require any changes.</p>
            <li>
              <p>
                <strong>Update documentation.</strong> Document the review and attach the review results to the network documentation. The staff member(s) responsible for the review should sign-off on the review results. </p>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>