<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-91623099" Content_Hash="-28811030">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>b247ef2a-12b4-4eb1-913f-2f3e4079468a</Id>
    <Id_History>e2bde779-f331-478d-afbf-e113f748fb15,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>Restrict User Access to System Level Resources</Title>
    <Category>Authorization</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>Web Application</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Restrict User Access to System Level Resources</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Michael Dunner, Srinath Vasireddy, Ray Escamilla and Anandha Murukan</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <div>Web Application</div>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Your design should identify all of the identities that the application uses, including the process identity, and any impersonated identities, including anonymous Internet user accounts and service identities. The design should also indicate to which resources these identities require access.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>If failing to lock down system resources against application identities, an attacker can coerce the application into accessing restricted system resources.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>When you design your application, consider the restrictions that will be placed on the application in terms of which system-level resources it can access.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>System level resources include files, folders, registry keys, Active Directory objects, database objects, event logs, and so on. Use Windows Access Control Lists (ACLs) to restrict which users can access what resources and the types of operations that they can perform. Pay particular attention to anonymous Internet user accounts; lock these down with ACLs on resources that explicitly deny access to anonymous users.</p>
  <br />
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>