<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="553455533" Content_Hash="1408535570">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>d3a0d366-49ae-4393-94b9-cffa4eed67a5</Id>
    <Id_History>23d81019-d4ce-4147-8987-efbccba2b92c,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>Configure the Windows Access Control System</Title>
    <Category>Configuration</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Configure the Windows Access Control System</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 7.2<li>PCI DSS Requirement 7.2.1<li>PCI DSS Requirement 7.2.2<li>PCI DSS Requirement 7.2.3</li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>
    <span>Configure the Windows access control system to comply with the PCI DSS Requirement 7.2.</span>
  </p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>
    <span>The access control lists implemented in Windows may be used to satisfy the PCI DSS Requirement 7.2 if properly configured.</span>
  </p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>
    <span>Perform the following tasks to configure the Windows access control system in compliance with PCI DSS:</span>
  </p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <strong>Set the deny-all default.&amp;nbsp;</strong> Right click on each drive or shared folder and select "Properties". Select the "Security" tab. Windows assigns some privileges by default. Remove the default Windows privileges where needed.&amp;nbsp;Remove all the access privileges that are not required for each user's job functions. An empty Windows access control lists default to deny-all.<li><p><strong>Define data access requirements.</strong> Prepare access authorization documents for each employee based on job-related needs for data access. Have management authorize&amp;nbsp;all data access authorization documents.</p><li><strong>Grant privileges. </strong>Review the access authorization documents for each user to determine the assigned privileges. Implement the assigned privileges using Windows access control lists.</li></li></li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <span>For more information about configuring the Windows Access Control System, please see "File and Folder Permissions" at <a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb727008.aspx">http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb727008.aspx</a>.</span>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>