<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="910359226" Content_Hash="-302207525">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>d4ce4080-2feb-434c-bbfe-b00549e099a7</Id>
    <Id_History>d4ce4080-2feb-434c-bbfe-b00549e099a7,0d73a4f5-70ce-4a71-a732-d3e217a16aac,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>[1612Dupe] Use Indirect Object References</Title>
    <Category>Authorization</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use Indirect Object References</DirectLink>
    <Tag>ASP.NET,ASP.NET 4.0,ASP</Tag>
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies To</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>ASP.NET 4.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Use indirect object references.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Using indirect object references makes it harder for an attacker to bypass security controls.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>Use indirect object references in all web applications.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>To use indirect object references:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify pages that use system objects.</strong> Make a list of pages that use files and databases.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify application assets.</strong> Make a list of files and database keys that are used by each page.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define lookup tables.</strong> Assign an identifier to each resource being accessed by each page. Write a function or a set of functions that translates these identifiers into object references.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Use lookup tables.</strong> Use the object identifiers assigned in step 3 as parameters when referencing system objects. Call the function that translates that identifier into a direct object reference to access data.</p>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Solution Example</h1>
  <p>Instead of using the resource's database key, a drop down list of six resources authorized for the current user could use numbers 1 to 6 to indicate the value the user selected. The application has to map the per-user indirect reference back to the actual database key on the server.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>