<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1925709554" Content_Hash="1082038198">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>d529cf98-3701-4691-b31a-81ba0129cd92</Id>
    <Id_History>962f2b54-8ec3-459f-9de0-bdeecbf46b06,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>Define Information Security Responsibilities</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Define Information Security Responsibilities</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 12.4</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Define information security responsibilities.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Perform the following actions to define information security responsibilities:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define responsibilities for managing policies and procedures. </strong>These responsibilities should include:</p>
    </li>
    <ul>
      <li>Creating information security policies and procedures <li>Distributing information security policies and procedures <li>Updating information security policies and procedures</li></li></li>
    </ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define responsibilities for monitoring logs and alerts.</strong> These responsibilities should include:</p>
    </li>
    <ul>
      <li>Monitoring logs and alerts <li>Analyzing security information <li>Distributing security information, such as warnings and status updates, to information security and management staff</li></li></li>
    </ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define responsibilities for incident response procedures.</strong> These responsibilities should include:</p>
    </li>
    <ul>
      <li>Creating incident response procedures <li>Distributing incident response procedures</li></li>
    </ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define responsibilities for user management.</strong> These responsibilities should include:</p>
    </li>
    <ul>
      <li>Creating user accounts <li>Modifying user accounts <li>Removing user accounts <li>Implementing authentication technologies</li></li></li></li>
    </ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define responsibilities for data access control.</strong> These responsibilities should include:</p>
    </li>
    <ul>
      <li>Management of access authorization forms <li>Implementation of access control systems. <li>Configuration of access control systems.</li></li></li>
    </ul>
  </ol>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>