<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-414134749" Content_Hash="-99988273">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>e165074d-4638-44bf-b846-467a35c0da4c</Id>
    <Id_History>2254b83c-080f-478a-9916-5c706a39c7cb,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use Appropriately Sized Keys</Title>
    <Category>Cryptography</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use Appropriately Sized Keys</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Srinath Vasireddy, Ashish Babbar, Rico Mariani, and Alex Mackman</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Use appropriate key sizes when working with cryptographic services, such that it should give you margin of safety without sacrificing too much performance.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Choosing a key size represents a trade-off between performance and security. If you choose a key that is too small, the data that you thought was well protected can be vulnerable to attack. If you choose a key that is too large, your system will be subject to a performance impact without a commensurate real-world improvement in security.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>When adding cryptographic support to your application.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>The appropriate key size changes based on the cryptographic algorithm in use, and also changes over time as machine processing speeds increase and attack techniques become more sophisticated. The following recommendations will give you a margin of safety without sacrificing too much performance: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>When you use an asymmetric algorithm (RSA), choose a 2048-bit key </li>
    <li>When you use a symmetric algorithm (AES), choose a 128-bit key</li>
  </ul>
  <br />
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>