<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1915131821" Content_Hash="-198972681">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>ed179f9c-63b9-4934-b893-5a2c7ec99766</Id>
    <Id_History>b4ac27e0-517d-4c4e-9e5a-95d3a0a0ac34,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>If You Use SQL Authentication, Protect Credentials on the Network</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ADO.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink />
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Blaine Wastell, Prashant Bansode, Chaitanya Bijwe</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>ADO.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>If your application is not located in a physically secure isolated data center and you use SQL authentication, you should use Internet Protocol Security (IPSec) or Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) to create an encrypted communication channel between the Web server and database server.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>When you connect to SQL Server with SQL authentication, the credentials are not encrypted prior to transmission across the network. If you do not secure your network channel with IPSec or SSL, an attacker can easily capture credentials by using a network monitor.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>This guideline should be followed whenver using SQL authentication.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Use SSL when you need granular channel protection for a particular application, instead of for all applications and services running on a computer. If you want to secure all of the IP traffic between the Web and database servers, use IPSec. You can also use IPSec to restrict which computers can communicate with one another. For example, you can help protect a database server by establishing a policy that permits requests only from a trusted client computer, such as an application or Web server. You can also restrict communication to specific IP protocols and TCP/UDP ports.</p>
  <blockquote>
    <b>Note</b>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;During login, the SQL Server client encrypts the login packet by using SSL if the server has a certificate available. This occurs regardless of whether encryption is enabled for the connection.</blockquote>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns & practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>