<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1152095356" Content_Hash="-1656302622">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>fd085260-a76c-4923-948d-8be705d3bfba</Id>
    <Id_History>fd085260-a76c-4923-948d-8be705d3bfba,fde6dbe9-79e5-4e79-aac8-0640de6121d4,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use Transport Security When Possible</Title>
    <Category>Communication Security</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>WCF</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use Transport Security When Possible</DirectLink>
    <Tag>WCF 3.5</Tag>
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Jason Taylor, Prashant Bansode, Carlos Farre, Madhu Sundararajan, Rob Boucher, Steve Gregersen</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Microsoft® Windows Communication Foundation (WCF) 3.5 
</li>
    <li>Microsoft Visual Studio® 2008</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>Consider using Transport security when possible.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>By using Transport security you can have better perfomance than&amp;nbsp;Message security. </p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>When you want to support point-point communication and you don't want to support intermediary scenarios or protocol transition.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Transport security secures the client-server communication channel using HTTPS and Transport Layer Security (TLS) over TCP. Transport Security is transport dependent and does not require that the communicating parties understand XML-level security concepts. This can improve the interoperability.</p>
  <p>Consider that, if you are using transport security you cannot use Service Credential Negotiation or authentication types such as Username or Issue Token (CardSpace).</p>
  <p>Use the following criteria to decide whether or not to use transport security:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Point-to-point. Transport security supports point-to-point communication and does not support intermediary scenarios or protocol transition.
</li>
    <li>Streaming. Transport security can support streaming data scenarios.
</li>
    <li>Binding limitations. Transport security does not work with the wsDualHttpBinding.
</li>
    <li>Authentication limitations. Transport security does not work with negotiation, username, Issue Token (CardSpace)&amp;nbsp; or Kerberos direct authentication<br /></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For more information on choosing a transport, see “Choosing a Transport”&amp;nbsp; at <a href="http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733769.aspx">http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms733769.aspx</a></li>
  </ul>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>