<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="682733273" Content_Hash="702142063">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>0bd58913-2516-4ad6-a949-036a85fc0153</Id>
    <Id_History>fb22da6b-bf1c-4315-83a5-7bc3486bf9ab,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Authentication And Authorization Policies Are Configurable</Title>
    <Category>Authorization</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>Java</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Authentication And Authorization Policies Are Configurable</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Java</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Verify that authentication and authorization policies are configurable.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Authentication and authorization policies should be configurable to make it possible for the customers to adapt the application's security to their environment.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>To verify that authentication and authorization policies are configurable:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify application requirements.</strong> Define options for configuring access control and authentication policies. At the very least, there should be an administration panel for managing user accounts and global application settings, and a page for users to manage their own accounts. </p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Identify administrative pages.</strong> Find the administration interface that is used to configure authentication and authorization policies.</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Review the administration interface.</strong> Test the functionality of the administration interface to make sure it satisfies the application requirements.</p>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>To make authentication and authorization policies configurable:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify application requirements.</strong> Define options for configuring access control and authentication policies. At the very least, there should be an administration panel for managing user accounts, and a page for users to manage their own accounts.</p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Make authentication and authorization code configurable.</strong> Find all code responsible for authentication and authorization features. Modify this code to read settings defined in the application requirements.</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Design the administrative pages.</strong> Design the pages to be used for configuring access control and authentication policies based on the requirements for your application.</p>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Implement the administration interface.</strong> Write code for the administrative pages to interface with authentication and authorization code. The administration interface should be able to read and write settings to a secure location, where the authentication and authorization code may access them. The saved settings should be protected with access controls to prevent unauthorized disclosure and tampering.</p>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Authorization Guidelines</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/127d98e8-d628-40b7-8522-d903f4bf7927">Perform Role-based Security Checks</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/afa2d020-9b18-4861-9d4f-cb81cbcb1f2e">Require Authentication and Authorization for All Sensitive Pages</a>
        <li>
          <a href="/article/12096ed3-d1e3-47e1-834d-f59dcaf4110f">Make Authentication and Authorization Policies Configurable</a>
          <li>
            <a href="/article/c0ff64c5-cf7f-4855-b039-81d2a298e3bb">Deny All Access by Default</a>
            <li>
              <a href="/article/92839e91-8f79-45fb-9b8d-76fc9c814fea">Check Access Control Permissions When Referencing Objects</a>
              <li>
                <a href="/article/b4a87891-a19a-41be-a1a3-f8a13c7f4881">Use Indirect Object References</a>
                <li>
                  <a href="/article/58e80d4a-410a-47c9-b3c5-f13cc79a3e00">Partition the Application Between Public and Private Domains</a>
                  <li>
                    <a href="/article/4b9647f2-644f-48bf-b2b5-cd025261450d">Secure the Account Administration Functionality</a>
                    <li>
                      <a href="/article/4f3147c2-7ca1-487c-9144-56630e5a6f80">Automatically Lock Inactive User Accounts</a>
                      <li>
                        <a href="/article/35bde9da-b8f2-4f8d-9a3f-48a3ededed4b">Consider Using JAAS for Authorization</a>
                      </li>
                    </li>
                  </li>
                </li>
              </li>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Authorization Checklists</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/14f55778-8227-4d0d-85ca-41d80853bc58">Role-based Security Checks Are Performed</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/0d7d5d60-33bc-4fac-a088-f0be84d37cef">Authentication and Authorization Are Required for All Sensitive Pages</a>
        <li>
          <a href="/article/fb22da6b-bf1c-4315-83a5-7bc3486bf9ab">Authentication and Authorization Policies Are Configurable</a>
          <li>
            <a href="/article/98e8c0d1-d95a-4eb7-a39b-630c40c7adaf">All Access Is Denied by Default</a>
            <li>
              <a href="/article/f3747faf-6e0b-43af-ae92-ed3736be390a">Access Control Permissions Are Checked When Referencing Objects</a>
              <li>
                <a href="/article/54ea1759-e5e8-4eee-84cc-67607fef0c30">Indirect Object References Are Used</a>
                <li>
                  <a href="/article/3e451992-d7aa-43fd-ade8-656a87b787f8">The Application Is Partitioned into Public and Private Domains</a>
                  <li>
                    <a href="/article/7cc251c5-6e57-47a6-976e-365e8830f958">Account Administration Functionality Is Secured</a>
                    <li>
                      <a href="/article/a4f21cca-3db6-4eae-88d2-5d6b5f7ad2bb">Inactive User Accounts Are Automatically Locked</a>
                    </li>
                  </li>
                </li>
              </li>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>