<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1485989754" Content_Hash="-566001988">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1a0203b1-2b5f-4680-aeeb-788c037d9aae</Id>
    <Id_History>c83cfd06-9c41-490b-b441-7fd04afa777b,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Logging Is Enabled</Title>
    <Category>Auditing and Logging</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Logging Is Enabled</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 10.1</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Logging should be enabled. A centralized log server should be deployed.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Logging helps detect an attack in progress, coordinate a response, and investigate the attack after the fact.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Locate and examine the centralized log server to verify that it is operational. Examine the logs to verify that they are current.&amp;nbsp;Interview the system administrator to verify that all system components are included in the logs.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Choose a centralized log server solution. When choosing a centralized log server solution, it may be helpful to verify that it is explicitly designed to satisfy PCI DSS Requirement 10.2.2 - logging all activity by the administrator and the other privileged users - because this functionality is difficult to implement otherwise. Install and configure a centralized log server by following the vendor's instructions. Configure all network devices that are compatible with the log server to send logs to the log server. Make a list of the incompatible devices and use this list daily to manually check and backup the corresponding logs. Consider replacing the devices that are not compatible with ones that are.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/4dd022f3-c917-40cc-ac40-c3055beaccac">Implement Audit Trails for System Components</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>