<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="420698779" Content_Hash="1584408346">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1bafcdcf-effc-4b9d-8933-24420a9d25ba</Id>
    <Id_History>e362bc93-5c6f-46c1-a530-a7d3c8caf017,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Default SNMP Community Strings Are Changed on Wireless Devices</Title>
    <Category>Configuration</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Default SNMP Community Strings Are Changed on Wireless Devices</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 2.1.1.b</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>The default SNMP community strings should be changed from vendor defaults on wireless access points.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>SNMP community strings act as passwords for SNMP-enabled devices, and the default settings can be found by potential attackers on the Internet. Changing SNMP community strings on wireless access points prevents a potential attacker from changing wireless settings or discovering sensitive network information.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Inspect the wireless access points to&amp;nbsp;check if&amp;nbsp;they have SNMP functionality. If the wireless access points have SNMP functionality, examine the configuration on each access point to make sure that the SNMP community string is changed from the vendor default. Use the Internet or the vendor's documentation to find out what the default SNMP community strings are and make sure that the ones in the current configuration are different.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Change the SNMP community string on each wireless access point to something other than the default. The SNMP community string is essentially a password, so the password policy should be followed when choosing a new SNMP community string. The exact steps required to change the SNMP community string vary by hardware. Please refer to the vendor's documentation or tech support for instructions on changing SNMP community strings on your wireless access points.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/82d643e8-97ab-4043-b6c1-04fb0a585f2d">Configure a Wireless Access Point for PCI DSS</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>