<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1638699777" Content_Hash="-274611523">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1ebca605-76ab-4f05-9c2a-8f1439786536</Id>
    <Id_History>46307952-1ccf-449e-9489-4d87753fcfd8,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Network Documentation Includes an Accurate Network Diagram</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Network Documentation Includes an Accurate Network Diagram</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.2.a <li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.2.b<li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.3.b</li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>The network documentation should include an up-to-date network diagram that documents all connections to cardholder data, including any wireless networks.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>The network diagram is useful for maintenance and security tasks. The network diagram can help with identifying potential vulnerabilities in the network design, planning changes to the network and performing routine maintenance tasks. The network diagram is required to pass the PCI DSS compliance certification&amp;nbsp;process.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Make sure there is a staff member maintaining network documentation. Make sure that the network documentation includes an up-to-date version of the network diagram, showing all connections to the cardholder data. Compare the network diagram to the physical network to make sure the diagram corresponds to reality.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Inspect each network device and diagram its relationship relative to all other network devices. Make sure to document all connections to cardholder data, including any wireless networks. Designate a staff member responsible for maintaining network documentation.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/ce7b9815-7f65-43b3-89d8-49fba5086e54">Prepare the Network Documentation for PCI DSS Compliance</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/e89569d5-1aea-49d3-913e-c9cf4a0f5b91">Draw a Network Diagram</a>
        <li>
          <a href="/article/fb495fcc-40f1-43e9-82f0-2c040a6d1653">Disable Unused Services and Protocols</a>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>