<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="2023658052" Content_Hash="1425523127">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>2007ed5b-dc40-4cbd-9ff6-49bb1b90bbf2</Id>
    <Id_History>adac60c7-9295-489c-a1c9-fd4078bbfe2d,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Custom Application Code Is Reviewed</Title>
    <Category>Deployment Considerations</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Custom Application Code Is Reviewed</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 6.3</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Verify that code&amp;nbsp;is reviewed by someone other than its author,&amp;nbsp;developed according to secure coding guidelines, corrections are implemented before the&amp;nbsp;release, and code review results&amp;nbsp;are approved by management before&amp;nbsp;the release.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Changes to application code should be reviewed to ensure that they do not introduce vulnerabilities.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Review the information security policy and the software develoment process&amp;nbsp;to make sure that code&amp;nbsp;is reviewed by someone other than its author,&amp;nbsp;developed according to secure coding guidelines, corrections&amp;nbsp;are implemented before the&amp;nbsp;release, and code review results should be approved by management before the release. Interview the development staff to make sure that they comply with the requirements in the information security policy when reviewing code changes.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Add a requirement to the information security policy that code changes should&amp;nbsp;reviewed by someone other than their author(s). Add steps to the software development process for someone other than the code's author review the code. It is a good idea to have a dedicated testing team in the development environment. Add a requirement to the information security policy for code to be developed according to secure coding principles. Integrate security engineering techniques with your software development process. Information about security engineering techniques may be found in TeamMentor in the "Security Engineering" folder. Add a requirement to the information security policy for corrections to be implemented before release. Add steps to the software development process to fix any errors found in the code during review to be fixed before the release. Add a requirement to the information security policy for&amp;nbsp;code review results to be approved by management before release. Add this requirement to the software development process.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>