<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-485299231" Content_Hash="-720749867">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>28070416-676a-45e2-8e58-2039540a2153</Id>
    <Id_History>13912b44-0b4e-4792-a649-ee6bc16a3ede,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>Mapping Values Are Used for Redirects And Forwards</Title>
    <Category>Redirects and Forwards</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Mapping Values Are Used for Redirects And Forwards</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies To</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Web Applications</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Verify that mapping values are used to determine destinations of redirects and forwards.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Using mapping values when performing redirects or forwards prevents malicious users from creating hyperlinks that use the redirects or forwards to point to pages other than those intended by the application design.</p>
  <h1>How To Check</h1>
  <p>Use the following steps to make sure that mapping values are used for redirects and forwards:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify redirects and forwards.</strong> Review code to find all redirects and forwards.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Examine redirects and forwards.</strong> Look for code that handles parameters. Verify that this code does not accept fully qualified URLs as input for calculating destinations of redirects or forwards. If code uses parameters to calculate destinations of redirects or forwards, verify that only short-hand keywords defined by the application are accepted as input to map to valid and authorized destinations.</p>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How To Fix</h1>
  <p>Perform the following actions to calculate destinations of redirects and forwards based on mapping values:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify redirects and forwards.</strong> Review code to find all redirects and forwards.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Enumerate destinations.</strong> Make a list of all destinations pointed to by redirects and forwards.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Define mapping values.</strong> Define mapping values for all destinations used by redirects and forwards. A mapping value is a short identifying string that symbolically represents a resource.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Rewrite redirects and forwards.</strong> Rewrite redirects and forwards to use mapping values as input to calculate the final destinations of redirects or forwards.</p>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <em>You may find these additional articles useful</em>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/2869a8f0-93b8-4689-b531-d59367988a33">Use Mapping Values When Redirecting on User Input</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/0ed7310a-a0fd-4074-9c0f-37f48cf2bf4f">Don't Use Redirects or Forwards if Possible</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/52982908-b692-41bc-afb1-8663e399c51c">Validate Destinations of Redirects and Forwards</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/32c35abe-a470-4a9c-8bb6-54c1461d3295">URL Redirection Attack</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/d4612e8e-78c6-444e-a252-45ab97616a0b">How to Test for URL Redirection Bugs</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/c8ae222b-ed2e-4621-a46b-3671f82f5a03">Phishing Attack</a>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <br />
  <h1>
  </h1>
  <h1>
  </h1>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>