<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1427743322" Content_Hash="1462434748">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>373a6238-430e-453b-886e-4a7c422ecbd1</Id>
    <Id_History>61e0e2b4-2f09-429a-b72f-f8933f2fa9b6,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Accounts Are Locked After Consecutive Failed Login Attempts</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>Java</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Accounts Are Locked After Consecutive Failed Login Attempts</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>2</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Ensure that accounts&amp;nbsp;are locked after consecutive failed login attempts. </p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Multiple, consecutive failed authentication attempts over a short period of time are a symptom that is used to detect when an account is under attack. Locking out the account prevents the attacker from compromising and accessing the account.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Follow these steps to ensure your application will lock out an account after consecutive failed login attempts:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Verify your application has a lockout policy. </strong>An account lockout policy is typically application specific. Review your application's requirements and design specifications and verify the&amp;nbsp;following functionality:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>A mechanism for determining failed authentication attempts <li>A mechanism for locking accounts that have exceeded the maximum number of allowed authentication attempts <li>A mechanism for unlocking accounts that have exceeded the maximum number of allowed authentication attempts</li></li></li>
      </ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Ensure your application tracks login attempts. </strong>All authentication procedures record the number of authentication attempts for each user. The login counter for each user&amp;nbsp;should be&amp;nbsp;reset to 0 upon a successful authentication</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Ensure your application enforces the lockout policy. </strong>All authentication procedures implement your application's lockout policy. The implementation should&amp;nbsp;match the lockout policy as the business requirements of your organization may change over time</p>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <p>
    <strong>Note:</strong> PCI DSS certification requires that logs should include failed access attempts, that a user gets locked out after no more than 6 failed login attempts, and the lockout lasts for&amp;nbsp;at least&amp;nbsp;30 minutes.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Use the following steps to successfully lock accounts after consecutive failed login attempts:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Determine a lockout policy. </strong>There are two variables to consider when determining a lockout policy:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Number of allowed consecutive failed login attempts <li>Amount of time that a locked account will remain locked</li></li>
      </ul>
      <p>A simple policy would be to lock an account after&amp;nbsp;five failed login attempts for the duration of 15 minutes. Although this is an effective method for blocking a brute force attack, it exposes your application to denial of service as an attacker can easily keep an account locked through a small stream of authentication requests.<br /><br />When determining the lockout policy, it is important to evaluate the risk of attacks against the user and the support costs associated with reactivating a locked account. For example, requiring the user to contact your organization's support staff&amp;nbsp;to reactivate a locked account will have a direct impact on support costs and would add general user frustration.&amp;nbsp;However, it is important to use extra care when designing more sophisticated variations of your application's lockout policy, such as correlating a single or multiple user login attempts with a source IP. When adding extra levels of complexity, carefully consider and evaluate the scenarios where your application's lockout policy can be circumvented or can harm your business. For instance, consider scenarios where an attacker would attempt to compromise a user through the use of multiple hosts, or multiple users would authenticate using a shared office IP.</p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Track login attempts. </strong>Login attempts can be tracked with the use of a login counter. Increment the counter once a user tries to authenticate. Reset the counter to 0 after the user successfully authenticates. Example:</p>
        <pre>-- Authenticate the user<br />sql&gt; select login_attempts from users<br />      where user = &amp;#123;&amp;#123;username&amp;#125;&amp;#125; and pass = &amp;#123;&amp;#123;passDigest&amp;#125;&amp;#125;;<br /> -- Reset the login counter<br />sql&gt; update users set login_attempts = 0 where user = &amp;#123;&amp;#123;username&amp;#125;&amp;#125;;</pre>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Enforce the lockout policy. </strong>The lockout policy should be enforced at all points in the application where authentication is necessary. Example:</p>
          <pre>String dbStatement = "select login_attempts from users"<br />                   &amp;#43; "where user = ? and pass = ?;";<br />PreparedStatement st = dbConnection.prepareStatement(dbStatement);<br />st.setString(1, user);st.setString(2, passDigest);<br />ResultSet rs = st.executeQuery();<br /><br />if (rs.first())<br />&amp;#123;      <br />userIsValid = true;<br />      loginCount = rs.getInt(1);<br />&amp;#125;<br />else<br />&amp;#123;<br />      userIsValid = false;<br />&amp;#125;<br /><br />rs.close();<br /><br />if(userIsValid)<br />&amp;#123;<br />      if(loginCount &gt; 3)<br />      &amp;#123;<br />            throw new AccountIsLockedException();<br />      &amp;#125;<br /><br />      // The application checks the password's maturity<br />      checkPasswordMaturity(user);<br />&amp;#125;<br />else<br />&amp;#123;<br />      updateLastLoginAttempt(user);<br />&amp;#125;</pre>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Set an unlocking mechanism. </strong>Keep track of the lockout period. Based on your application's lockout policy, unlock the account after the lockout period has expired. Example:</p>
            <pre>-- Unlock all locked accounts whose 45 minute lockout period has expired<br />sql&gt; update users set login_attempts = 0<br />      where last_login &lt; (current_timestamp - interval '45' minute);</pre>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <p>
    <strong>Note:</strong> PCI DSS requirements state that an account should be locked out for at least 30 minutes after no more than six failed login attempts.</p>
  <h1>Problem Example</h1>
  <p>The following code executes the database transaction that is required during authentication. Because the transaction fails to check the login attempts counter, it is possible for an attacker to compromise an account through the use of brute force or a dictionary attack.</p>
  <pre>// The application fails to check the number of login attempts<br />String dbStatement = "select user from users where user = ? and pass = ?;";<br />st = dbConnection.prepareStatement(dbStatement);<br />st.setString(1, user);<br />st.setString(2, passDigest);<br />rs = st.executeQuery();</pre>
  <h1>Solution Example</h1>
  <p>The following code executes the database transaction that is required during authentication. Because the transaction checks the login attempts counter, it would be very expensive for an attacker to compromise an account through the use of brute force or a dictionary attack.</p>
  <pre>// The application checks the number of login attempts<br />String dbStatement = "select login_attempts from users where user = ? and pass = ?;";<br />PreparedStatement st = dbConnection.prepareStatement(dbStatement);<br />st.setString(1, user);<br />st.setString(2, passDigest);<br />ResultSet rs = st.executeQuery();<br /><br />if (rs.first())<br />&amp;#123;<br />      userIsValid = true;<br />      loginCount = rs.getInt(1);<br />&amp;#125;<br />else<br />&amp;#123;<br />      userIsValid = false;<br />&amp;#125;<br /><br />rs.close();<br /><br />if(userIsValid)<br />&amp;#123;<br />      if(loginCount &gt; 3)<br />      &amp;#123;<br />            throw new AccountIsLockedException();<br />      &amp;#125;<br />      checkPasswordMaturity(user);<br />&amp;#125;<br />else<br />&amp;#123;<br />      updateLastLoginAttempt(user);<br />&amp;#125;</pre>
  <h1>Authentication Guidelines</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/989e27ec-ffdf-4006-88bd-1c09fc991a28">Centralize Authentication Controls</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/d3a69ef7-2c63-41bc-81e4-803b0ea199d8">Use Server-side Authentication</a>
        <li>
          <a href="/article/38d12903-9c3b-46bd-9f5e-f223c3272624">Make Sure Authentication Controls Fail Securely</a>
          <li>
            <a href="/article/84fd606b-e2f2-4c48-9c6e-6b5e780c6163">Force Re-authentication When Executing Critical Functionality</a>
            <li>
              <a href="/article/c566cabe-2463-4d24-8763-22e8468d167e">Validate Usernames Before Processing Them</a>
              <li>
                <a href="/article/7ba2d49c-ff53-4755-97ae-0efcb0aa9c22">Lock Accounts After Consecutive Failed Login Attempts</a>
                <li>
                  <a href="/article/4b5b1f05-aa9a-4ebc-8b2e-3cecabed03e1">Enforce Strong Passwords</a>
                  <li>
                    <a href="/article/ea25af24-8eca-45ad-9f41-94bad8880247">Force Password Renewal</a>
                    <li>
                      <a href="/article/c7825052-f281-4ac8-a786-41b776219af6">Mask All Password Fields</a>
                      <li>
                        <a href="/article/c4d9269f-9157-4919-952c-f0d14ccd7f60">Verify the Application's Authenticity to the User</a>
                        <li>
                          <a href="/article/b4f83e8e-3223-4e49-bc9c-56c8c7268582">Place Logout Links on All Pages that Require Authentication</a>
                          <li>
                            <a href="/article/ff95311e-797f-417f-bd0b-e6cf610f706c">Do Not Leave Passwords in Memory</a>
                            <li>
                              <a href="/article/bcf8adb4-8186-4b97-b490-4fa33f506bfd">Limit Access to the Credential Store</a>
                              <li>
                                <a href="/article/0dba2e1f-7d49-4d91-bc93-ad85480f784a">Consider Using JAAS for Authentication</a>
                                <li>
                                  <a href="/article/9cf8aed6-22a5-49c1-a0ce-1d8e5366bebf">Consider Using Two Factor Authentication</a>
                                </li>
                              </li>
                            </li>
                          </li>
                        </li>
                      </li>
                    </li>
                  </li>
                </li>
              </li>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Authentication Checklists</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/4e431329-73aa-41f7-b397-9b7e26294a4c">Authentication Controls Are Centralized</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/b103207d-73e3-4964-9a00-2b15c3e012b8">Server-side Authentication Is Used</a>
        <li>
          <a href="/article/ded06846-ad7f-4044-87d2-8bbb6b885713">Authentication Controls Fail Securely</a>
          <li>
            <a href="/article/df093ee3-ad7b-4191-935c-8bb0cad78d98">Re-authentication Is Enforced When Executing Critical Functionality</a>
            <li>
              <a href="/article/f8586505-72f9-4c14-a365-3e5049e5ca57">Usernames Are Validated Before Use</a>
              <li>
                <a href="/article/61e0e2b4-2f09-429a-b72f-f8933f2fa9b6">Accounts Are Locked After Consecutive Failed Login Attempts</a>
                <li>
                  <a href="/article/7401862f-ae81-4f31-9340-981b0ec5a854">Strong Passwords Are Enforced</a>
                  <li>
                    <a href="/article/12889762-1d65-4b7d-a90a-58ff6c23d1e4">Password Renewal Is Enforced</a>
                    <li>
                      <a href="/article/09f994c9-a401-404c-bdc9-210038eba658">All Password Fields Are Masked</a>
                      <li>
                        <a href="/article/35851f18-13a0-4bf8-88cc-d35c371cfb12">The Application's Authenticity Is Verified to the User</a>
                        <li>
                          <a href="/article/493e0e57-254a-4697-8fa1-c93e706d416d">All Pages that Use Authentication Have Logout Links</a>
                          <li>
                            <a href="/article/55488f2e-ed85-4f0f-9f83-1d90a5d10bd0">Passwords Are Not Left in Memory</a>
                            <li>
                              <a href="/article/9031f577-80b0-4a2e-9652-7b470439a0df">Access to the Credential Store Is Limited</a>
                            </li>
                          </li>
                        </li>
                      </li>
                    </li>
                  </li>
                </li>
              </li>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Authentication Testing</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/f32846cf-35f6-40fe-8517-f0ac8a415383">How to Test for Account Lockout Bugs in Java</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>