<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1132530584" Content_Hash="1282313149">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>408e9c62-0ce9-4d89-bde2-a1abafc0e790</Id>
    <Id_History>c3480653-5c08-4ac0-8037-a012f9524db4,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>The Cardholder Data Environment Doesn't Have Direct Internet Access</Title>
    <Category>Communication Security</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>The Cardholder Data Environment Doesn't Have Direct Internet Access</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.3.3</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>The cardholder data environment should not have direct Internet access. Neither outbound nor inbound traffic should be routable between the cardholder data environment and the Internet.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Denying the cardholder data environment Internet connectivity prevents the potential attacker from being able to conduct attacks against it.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Check the router and firewall configurations to make sure there are no port-forwarding rules or gateways that allow inbound connections directly to the cardholder data environment. Use built-in operating system tools (such as ping, traceroute, nslookup) to make sure that the cardholder data environment has no Internet access. </p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Remove any routes from the router configuration that allow Internet access to the cardholder data environment. Remove any port forwarding rules from the firewalls and/or routers that allow Internet access to the cardholder data environment. Repeat the How to Check processes to ensure that&amp;nbsp;changes have not accidentally introduced Internet connectivity in the cardholder environment.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/b5797c0e-fdaf-4c66-b2fb-134946ad703c">Configure the Routers for PCI DSS Compliance</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>