<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-394693655" Content_Hash="480271168">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>45a3925d-6bc3-4dab-83c6-01326a1bde3f</Id>
    <Id_History>d52c0752-9f54-4cb6-affd-51526bea0dd7,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Penetration Tests Are Performed Regularly</Title>
    <Category>Deployment Considerations</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Penetration Tests Are Performed Regularly</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 11.3 </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Penetration tests should be performed at least once a year and after any significant changes to the network.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Penetration tests may expose security vulnerabilities and misconfigurations. Penetration tests exercise the response capabilities of the company to verify that they are sufficient for handling an actual attack.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Use the following steps to check if penetration tests are performed regularly:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Review policy.</strong> Examine the information security policy to verify that it requires:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Penetration tests to be performed at least once a year and after any significant changes to the network <li>All found vulnerabilities to be fixed <li>Tests to be repeated until no more vulnerabilities are found</li></li></li>
      </ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Review Documentation. </strong>Examine the results of the previous penetration tests to verify that they have been performed regularly and the discovered vulnerabilities were corrected.</p>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Perform the following tasks to assure that penetration tests are performed regularly:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Update policy.</strong> Add&amp;nbsp;requirements to the information security policy to </p>
      <ul>
        <li>Conduct penetration tests at least once a year&amp;nbsp;and after any significant changes to the network <li>Fix all found vulnerabilities <li>Repeat testing until no more vulnerabilities are found</li></li></li>
      </ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Schedule penetration tests.</strong> Hire a qualified company to perform penetration tests. Perform penetration tests regularly, document the results, and attach them to the security documentation.</p>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/8659f8ec-ade6-4388-b846-4c833a23d51e">Perform Penetration Tests</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>