<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-402062606" Content_Hash="417800362">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>466775f5-9c26-4ba8-a2b2-e67d92eb758c</Id>
    <Id_History>0e1c3609-d978-4cbc-88e8-2436214c041d,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>There Is a Formal Process for Testing Changes to the Firewall Configuration</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Test</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>There Is a Formal Process for Testing Changes to the Firewall Configuration</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.1.1</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Ensure that the network documentation and the Information Security policy include a requirement for a formal process for testing changes to the firewall configuration. Verify that the network documentation includes directions for a procedure to test changes to the firewall configuration.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Changes to the firewall configuration must be tested to make sure that vulnerabilities are not introduced inadvertently by the changes made to the firewall configuration.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Examine the network documentation and the Information Security policy to make sure they include a requirement and a description of a process to test changes to the firewall configuration.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Add a point to the&amp;nbsp;Information Security policy to require following a specific process to test changes to the firewall configuration whenever changes to the firewall configuration are being made.&amp;nbsp;Describe a process for testing changes to the firewall configuration in the network documentation.&amp;nbsp;Perform a test run of the testing process to make sure that the process is adequate for your network. For help with implementing a process to test changes to the firewall configuration, please refer to the guideline article "Test Changes to the Firewall Configuration," linked below.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/ef539bda-a016-4362-b1b7-3b9529acf92a">Test Changes to the Firewall Configuration</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>