<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1500807625" Content_Hash="1007132873">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>48eebafa-b647-426f-a630-c2952cb4c41c</Id>
    <Id_History>51a93164-b557-43d3-b103-48771f3efa67,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>92718d53-36b2-47bc-b6f5-e60994385f46</Library_Id>
    <Title>Where Appropriate, the System.Net.Security.NegotiateStream Class Is Used for a TCP Channel with .NET Remoting.</Title>
    <Category>Communication Security</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET 3.5</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Where Appropriate, the System.Net.Security.NegotiateStream Class Is Used for a TCP Channel with .NET Remoting.</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Check to ensure that the System.Net.Security.NegotiateStream class is used for a TCP channel with .NET remoting to encrypt and to authenticate callers.</p>
  <p />
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Remoting applications that use the TCP channel do not by default perform authentication or encryption. In the .NET Framework, the remoting framework uses the <b>System.Net.Security.NegotiateStream</b> class to encrypt and sign the data transported over the channel and to authenticate callers. To use this feature, you can configure the &lt;<b>channel</b>&gt; element in the Machine.config file, the Web.config file, or the App.config file, depending on whether you want to apply the setting across all applications on your computer or to a specific application.</p>
  <p>The following example shows how a server specifies that authentication is required and that the channel should be protected with encryption.</p>
  <div>
    <pre>&lt;channel ref="tcp" port="1234"<br />          authenticationMode="IdentifyCallers" secure="true" /&gt;  </pre>
  </div>
  <p>To authenticate clients by using their domain credentials, you need to set the <b>useDefaultCredentials</b> attribute of the &lt;<b>channel</b>&gt; in the client configuration to true. The following example shows a sample client configuration.</p>
  <div>
    <pre>&lt;channel ref="tcp" useDefaultCredentials="true" secure="true"<br />          impersonationLevel="Identify" /&gt;  </pre>
  </div>
  <p>To use Kerberos authentication, the client must specify a service principal name (SPN). This can be done programmatically or in the client's configuration file, as shown in the following example.</p>
  <div>
    <pre>&lt;channel ref="tcp"<br />          useDefaultCredentials="true"<br />          impersonationLevel="Identify"<br />          spn="someService/somehost.com" /&gt;  </pre>
  </div>
  <blockquote>
    <b>Note</b>&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Use of .NET remoting is not encouraged for interprocess or server-to-server communication. .NET remoting is for cross-application domain communication within a process.</blockquote>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>