<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-461704736" Content_Hash="799893634">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>4bcde2ae-371f-444e-b26c-4d6480bbc7fa</Id>
    <Id_History>5290cfd7-e0f7-492c-ac67-1d70949f08ea,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>The Information Security Policy Is PCI DSS Compliant</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>The Information Security Policy Is PCI DSS Compliant</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 12.1 <li>PCI DSS Requirement 12.1.1 <li>PCI DSS Requirement 12.1.2 <li>PCI DSS Requirement 12.1.3</li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Information security policy should be PCI DSS compliant.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Use the following steps to verify that the information security policy is compliant with PCI DSS:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Check that the information security policy has been published.</strong> Verify that&amp;nbsp;the information security policy&amp;nbsp;has been published and disseminated to all relevant users by interviewing the staff responsible for maintaining the policy and checking their records. </p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Check that the information security policy&amp;nbsp;addresses all PCI DSS requirements.</strong> Get a copy of the PCI DSS document. Go through the information security policy and cross out the PCI DSS requirements that are covered by each respective policy requirement. After going through the entire information security policy, all PCI DSS requirement should be crossed out. </p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Check that annual risk assessment is required.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Examine the information security policy to verify that it includes a definition of a formal risk assessment and requires the assessment to be performed annually. </p>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Check that policy is maintained.</strong> Interview the staff responsible for maintaining the information security policy to verify that they review the policy at least annually and that they update the policy when needed.</p>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Perform the following tasks to assure that the information security policy is compliant with PCI DSS:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Publish the information security policy.</strong> Write, publish and distribute an information security policy to all the important users. Follow the instructions in the article linked to at the bottom of this page to add requirements to the policy to make sure that it covers all PCI DSS requirements. </p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Delegate responsibility for maintaining the information security policy. </strong>Delegate responsibility for maintaining the information security policy up-to-date to qualified&amp;nbsp;staff and instruct them to review the information security policy annually and to update it as needed. </p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Conduct an annual risk assessment.</strong> Define an annual risk assessment process. This process should consist of a vulnerability scan and a penetration scan. Add the definition and a requirement to carry out the assessment annually to the information security policy. </p>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Conduct an annual review.</strong> Schedule the annual information security policy review.</p>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/0b12299f-7d22-4fae-886a-38123b56ac90">Maintain a PCI DSS Compliant Information Security Policy</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>