<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1801364971" Content_Hash="-1511875003">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>53801ed7-811e-4180-b0e2-0a9297d4d88f</Id>
    <Id_History>404c5f16-2423-4f1f-9b11-004065a3dd7b,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Policy Defines Daily Security Procedures</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Policy Defines Daily Security Procedures</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 12.2</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Policy should define daily security procedures.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Daily procedures should be clearly defined so that people&amp;nbsp;can carry them out consistently and in a timely fashion.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Examine the information security documentation to make sure it includes clear definitions of daily operating procedures that cover all applicable PCI DSS requirements. The following procedures should be defined:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Updating the anti-virus <li>Updating software <li>Identifying new vulnerabilities <li>Managing physical access <li>Backing up&amp;nbsp;logs <li>Reviewing Logs <li>Managing the incident response plan <li>Managing encryption keys <li>Assigning unique user IDs <li>Managing&amp;nbsp;user accounts <li>Handling visitors <li>Maintaining the visitor log <li>Secure media distribution <li>Authorization for moving data <li>Destroying media containing cardholder data <li>Performing background checks <li>Educating staff on security policies <li>Managing service providers</li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Document the procedures for each of the daily tasks that must be performed within your company and include them in your information security policy. The exact definitions should be specific to your company. Train the staff that corresponds to each procedure to ensure a consistent and timely execution of each task.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/f2d2b7dc-a835-4eb3-a5c4-8423a3d8b69c">Define Daily Security Operational Procedures</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>