<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-11087507" Content_Hash="43148649">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>53f237a7-6e0d-4cab-8f57-c5676a8619cc</Id>
    <Id_History>43b02dbd-a3cd-4020-87d5-2b82acfbd8ae,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Strong Cryptography Is Used to Secure Network Traffic</Title>
    <Category>Communication Security</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Strong Cryptography Is Used to Secure Network Traffic</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 4.1<li>PCI DSS Requirement 4.1.a</li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Strong cryptography should be used whenever cardholder data is being transmitted over open, public networks.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Encrypt the cardholder data when transmitting to prevent it from being read if intercepted by an attacker.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Identify if and how the cardholder data is transmitted over open, public networks, such as the Internet. Identify all the computers that are involved in the transmission. Make sure that a strong encryption solution is used on each involved computer to secure the transmission. Some acceptable network encryption solutions are IPsec and SSL.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Identify if and how the cardholder data is transmitted over open, public networks, such as the Internet. Identify all the computers that are involved in the transmission. Choose a strong encryption solution to secure the transmission. Some acceptable encryption solutions are IPsec and&amp;nbsp;SSL: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <strong>IPsec</strong> is best used with VPN. IPSec is only an option when all hosts involved have static IPs.<li><strong>SSL </strong>is best used for transmitting data between a web client and a web server. </li></li>
  </ul>
  <p>Install and configure a strong encryption solution on each involved computer to secure the transmission.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/de1299b9-854b-4479-9f26-bbc9df38af29">Use SSL or IPSec for Secure Communication Between Entities</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>