<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1235851493" Content_Hash="1716635927">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>5dbc69bb-0ea8-436e-9cb5-01099eb0278f</Id>
    <Id_History>85e945d1-509d-4136-a4f8-63e44061d5aa,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Visitor Information Is Logged</Title>
    <Category>Deployment Considerations</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Visitor Information Is Logged</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 9.4 <li>PCI DSS Requirement 9.4.a <li>PCI DSS Requirement 9.4.b</li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Check that visitor information is logged and stored for at least three months. Verify that the visitor log includes each visitor's name, the firm represented, and the name of the employee authorizing access.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Visitor information should be logged to assist with an audit if needed. In the event of a compromise, the list of visitors provides a list of suspects.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Examine the visitor log to verify that it exists and has information for at least the past three months. Review the visitor log to make sure it includes the following information about each visitor: the visitor's name, the firm represented, and the name the employee authorizing access. </p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Start a visitor's log, recording the following information for each visitor: the visitor's name, the firm represented, and the name of the employee authorizing access. One way of keeping a visitor log is to make a spreadsheet with columns for the required information, print it out, give it to the receptionist, and ask visitors to fill it out before granting them access.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/8e669f6c-c528-41bb-a675-5f3e5f88dbc4">Implement Physical Security Controls</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>