<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-482249194" Content_Hash="315331823">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>7a55572d-193a-4ab5-bb18-40c1d4118c2a</Id>
    <Id_History>3301f14e-a836-4c6f-8704-17a6e63dbea2,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>Firewalls Between Wireless Networks And the Cardholder Data Environment</Title>
    <Category>Communication Security</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Firewalls Between Wireless Networks And the Cardholder Data Environment</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 1.2.3</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Firewalls should be installed between any wireless networks and the cardholder data environment. These firewalls should only allow traffic necessary for business purposes.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Wireless access points may be compromised and an attacker may be using them. To prevent sensitive data from leaking out through a compromised wireless network, a firewall should be used to filter traffic between the cardholder data environment and the wireless network.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>For each wireless network, find the firewall that is supposed to filter traffic between the cardholder data environment and the wireless network. Ensure that the firewall only allows traffic for business purposes. Refer to the vendor&amp;#8217;s documentation or technical support with configuration questions.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Install and configure a firewall between each wireless network and the cardholder data environment. Refer to the vendor&amp;#8217;s documentation or technical support for installation and configuration instructions.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/ef332991-e17c-492f-8560-7575155841c7">Configure the Firewalls for PCI DSS Compliance</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>