<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="412433128" Content_Hash="1695945060">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>7e316ef1-b47c-49f7-8e34-1ed03de33be6</Id>
    <Id_History>c91cf4f3-840c-4bb2-92ee-37a065cb7715,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Outside Resources Are Used to Track Vulnerabilities</Title>
    <Category>Deployment Considerations</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Outside Resources Are Used to Track Vulnerabilities</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 6.2</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>The staff should use outside resources to stay informed about the latest discovered security vulnerabilities.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>The information security community is very active on-line and provides many valuable resources for tracking the latest discovered vulnerabilities. Potential attackers monitor these resources, so it is important to mitigate these new threats before they are exploited.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Interview the staff and ask them what outside resources they use to stay informed about the latest discovered security vulnerabilities.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Add a requirement to the information security policy for the responsible staff to use outside resources to stay informed about the latest discovered security vulnerabilities. Instruct the staff to review on-line security vulnerability tracking resources periodically. Instruct at least one staff member to sign up for the BugTraq mailing list and other similar mailing lists as appropriate. Update configuration standards in the network documentation as appropriate to mitigate the newly discovered vulnerabilities.</p>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>To sign up for the BugTraq mailing list, please visit "Security Focus" at <a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/">http://www.securityfocus.com</a><li>For a list of recently discovered vulnerabilities, please see "Security Focus Vulnerabilities" at <a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/vulnerabilities">http://www.securityfocus.com/vulnerabilities</a><li>To check the latest public exploits, please see "PacketStorm" at <a href="http://www.packetstormsecurity.org/exploits100.html">http://www.packetstormsecurity.org/exploits100.html</a></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/e59af9c0-eaed-48a8-bae6-39f14dcb853d">Keep Track of New Security Vulnerabilities</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>