<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="960498644" Content_Hash="1797162119">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>82d4bad0-bf35-4234-9312-4fb48ad1e613</Id>
    <Id_History>c6193a48-9d2a-492b-a60f-26cb38f0c8ce,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>The PAN Is Unreadable Whenever It Is Stored</Title>
    <Category>Documentation and Policy</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>The PAN Is Unreadable Whenever It Is Stored</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 3.4<li>PCI DSS Requirement 3.4.a<li>PCI DSS Requirement 3.4.b<li>PCI DSS Requirement 3.4.c<li>PCI DSS Requirement 3.4.d</li></li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>The PAN should be rendered unreadable whenever it is stored.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>The PAN should be rendered unreadable whenever it is stored to prevent disclosure in the event of a successful compromise.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Identify if and where the PAN is stored. Examine a sample of database tables or files to verify that PAN is not stored in plain-text. Examine a sample of removable media that contains PAN information, if any, to confirm that the PAN is rendered unreadable. Examine a sample of the system logs to verify that the PAN is rendered unreadable or removed from the logs. Identify the mechanism used to secure the PAN. The acceptable mechanisms are: one-way crypto-hashes, truncation, index tokens and pads, and strong cryptography.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Identify if and where the PAN is stored. Choose one of the following mechanisms to protect the PAN: one-way crypto-hashes, truncation, index tokens and pads, and strong cryptography. Implement the chosen mechanism.</p>
  <p />
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/d74a788a-2b59-4dff-b5ca-ab65eba6cd49">Prepare the Data Retention and Disposal Policies</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>