<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="518000066" Content_Hash="156046940">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>8398aca1-08bb-4b1c-8d95-451d127f134a</Id>
    <Id_History>8398aca1-08bb-4b1c-8d95-451d127f134a,6ee4bf4b-90a2-44cc-870e-7f7ede7b6616,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>92718d53-36b2-47bc-b6f5-e60994385f46</Library_Id>
    <Title>Applications Using Medium Trust Are Isolated in Hosted Environments</Title>
    <Category>Code Access Security</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET 3.5</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Applications Using Medium Trust Are Isolated in Hosted Environments</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>2</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Ensure that your application uses medium trust in shared hosting environments.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>In ASP.NET,&nbsp;the SQL Server managed data provider no longer demands full trust, so SQL Server database access is available to medium trust applications. If you need to isolate multiple applications on a shared server from one another, as well as&nbsp;from shared system resources, use medium trust.</p>
  <p>To enforce medium trust for all Web applications on a server, use the following configuration in the machine-level Web.config file:</p>
  <p>
    <pre>&lt;location allowOverride="false"&gt;<br />  &lt;system.web&gt;<br />   &lt;trust level="Medium" originUrl="" /&gt;<br />  &lt;/system.web&gt;<br /> &lt;/location&gt;  </pre>
  </p>
  <p>By setting <b>allowOverride="false"</b>, an individual developer is unable to override the medium trust policy setting in his or her application's Web.config file.</p>
  <p>Medium trust provides application isolation because it restricts file system access to the application's own virtual directory hierarchy, and it limits access to HTTP Web resources to a defined address or set of addresses specified by the originUrl attribute on the &lt;trust&gt; element. It also prevents access to shared system resources such as the Windows event log and registry. Additionally, Medium trust applications cannot use reflection and cannot access non-SQL Server OLE DB data sources.</p>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns & practices guidance. </p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>