<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="2023232138" Content_Hash="1951570748">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>8a5c4e23-3395-4ba4-97b4-3e3569f39879</Id>
    <Id_History>8a5c4e23-3395-4ba4-97b4-3e3569f39879,02f72e42-e36d-4407-b812-fe2591269631,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>[SINK] Appropriate Key Sizes Are Used.</Title>
    <Category>Cryptography</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET 3.5</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Appropriate Key Sizes Are Used.</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Check to ensure that your application uses appropriate key sizes based on the cryptographic algorithm.</p>
  <p />
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Choosing a key size represents a trade-off between performance and security. If you choose a key that is too small, the data that you thought was well protected can be vulnerable to attack. If you choose a key that is too large, your system will be subject to a performance impact without a commensurate real-world improvement in security. The appropriate key size changes based on the cryptographic algorithm in use, and also changes over time as machine processing speeds increase and attack techniques become more sophisticated. The following recommendations will give you a margin of safety without sacrificing too much performance: </p>
  <ul>
    <li>When you use RSA as an asymmetric algorithm, choose a 2048-bit key <li>When you use AES as a symmetric algorithm, choose a 128-bit key <li>Other algorithms will have other key sizes. For the latest recommendations from Microsoft, see the CryptDeriveKey function definition at MSDN here - <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa379916(VS.85).aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/aa379916(VS.85).aspx</a></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>