<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="80459152" Content_Hash="-1188582987">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>8ff2cc67-8af8-4e12-890e-d389154a7bf3</Id>
    <Id_History>32dcee52-4916-483f-9489-3a9d92ea601d,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>Off-site Backups Are Encrypted</Title>
    <Category>Encryption</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Off-site Backups Are Encrypted</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Verify that off-site backups are encrypted.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Off-site backups should be encrypted to protect them if they are physically stolen. Encryption keys should be encrypted and stored separately to make sure that if the data backups are stolen, the attackers don't have the keys to go with them.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>To verify that off-site backups are encrypted:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify data to backup. </strong>Make a list of assets that should be backed up off-site.</p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Identify the encryption suite.</strong> Identify the software solution used to encrypt off-site backups. Make sure that strong encryption algorithms (AES-256) are used.</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Examine key management procedures.</strong> Make sure that key management procedures for keys used to secure off-site backups are established. The key management procedures should include procedures for changing the keys, backing up the keys, and securing the keys.</p>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Identify the off-site backup storage location.</strong> Find out where off-site backups are stored. Verify that the off-site backup storage facility is secure.</p>
            <li>
              <p>
                <strong>Identify the off-site encryption key storage location.</strong> Find out where the encryption keys used to encrypt off-site backups are stored. Verify that the location of the encryption keys is secure and separate from the location where off-site backups are kept.</p>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>To protect off-site backups:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify data to backup.</strong> Make a list of assets that should be backed up off-site.</p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Choose an encryption mechanism.</strong> Choose a software suite to use for encrypting off-site backups. Make sure that strong encryption algorithms (AES-256) are used.</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Establish key management.</strong> Define key management procedures for managing encryption keys used to protect off-site backups.</p>
          <li>
            <p>
              <strong>Choose an off-site storage location for the data.</strong> Choose a safe location for off-site backups. One example is a safe deposit box</p>
            <li>
              <p>
                <strong>Choose an off-site storage location for the keys.</strong> Choose a safe location for storing keys for off-site backups, separately from the backups themselves. One example is a safe deposit box. Make sure to store the encryption keys at a separate location from the encrypted backups.</p>
              <li>
                <p>
                  <strong>Encrypt and backup data.</strong> Establish a schedule for backing up data and encrypting the backups. Make sure that key management procedures are followed - keys are changed and backed up as necessary. Take the encrypted backups to the off-site storage location.</p>
                <li>
                  <p>
                    <strong>Encrypt and backup encryption keys.</strong> Establish a schedule for backing up and storing the encryption keys used to encrypt off-site backups. Take the encryption keys to an off-site location separate from the backups themselves.</p>
                </li>
              </li>
            </li>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Related Guidelines</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/8fb78275-ced7-491c-a6ba-25d34c2c2f9f">Consider the Threats to Data</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/5d3dc146-9274-430d-b357-7ee8ea0c082f">Hash and Salt Passwords for Storage</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/6e0918c1-90db-46d5-9f0e-8a98ddbcd7d5">Hash and Salt Passwords</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/66df6465-5476-4b55-90c8-ffbd7d556205">Use Strong Symmetric Encryption</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/f5cdd292-6f61-4584-b014-fc5134a3f9bc">Use Strong Asymmetric Encryption</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/5cc75586-f379-4b52-9b9f-365f6e470b68">Encrypt Off-site Backups</a>
    </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Checklists</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/a3472ce5-3618-4248-a33c-5acac47e1cf3">Threats to Data Are Considered</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/40bd25d2-b702-48b7-9102-bbbe674d6179">Passwords Are Hashed and Salted for Storage</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/d74fe6bf-387f-4ff1-9edb-d0275eedffc0">Passwords Are Hashed and Salted</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/23019ede-9f30-4709-997d-586475a2e626">Strong Symmetric Encryption Is Used</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/14a46517-6c86-498e-8429-1cb5ca3ce7c1">Strong Asymmetric Encryption Is Used</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>