<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1903743909" Content_Hash="560149507">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>9292148a-6560-4b08-80f7-26652e00576b</Id>
    <Id_History>bacd5fec-8a61-4aba-9ddf-017b65394a0a,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Staff Checks for New Vulnerabilities</Title>
    <Category>Deployment Considerations</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Staff Checks for New Vulnerabilities</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 6.2 </li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Processes should be in place to keep the staff informed of the latest discovered security vulnerabilities. Such processes may involve signing up for a mailing list and visiting web-sites focused on security.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>The information security community is very active on-line and provides many valuable resources for tracking the latest discovered vulnerabilities. Potential attackers monitor these resources, so it is important to mitigate these new threats before they are exploited.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Interview the responsible personnel and ask them what resources they use to keep track of the newly discovered security vulnerabilities. </p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Add a requirement to the information security policy for the responsible staff members to use outside resources to stay informed about the latest discovered security vulnerabilities. Instruct the staff to review on-line security vulnerability tracking resources periodically. Instruct at least one staff member to sign up for the BugTraq mailing list and other similar mailing lists as appropriate.</p>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>To sign up for the BugTraq mailing list, please visit "Security Focus" at <a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/">http://www.securityfocus.com</a><li>For a list of recently discovered vulnerabilities, please see "Security Focus Vulnerabilities" at <a href="http://www.securityfocus.com/vulnerabilities">http://www.securityfocus.com/vulnerabilities</a><li>To check the latest public exploits, please see "PacketStorm" at <a href="http://www.packetstormsecurity.org/exploits100.html">http://www.packetstormsecurity.org/exploits100.html</a></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/bcd191e0-9b2c-46b9-9288-af5fe412d01f">Keep Track of New Security Vulnerabilities</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>