<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1445465142" Content_Hash="247111689">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>a9cf382c-205f-459e-b1e4-327010377461</Id>
    <Id_History>572f0a14-3839-4289-a7c6-1f498696f6e5,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>51eb81c3-1d23-4146-ba83-8a6bb9233c11</Library_Id>
    <Title>An IDS Or IPS Is Deployed</Title>
    <Category>Auditing and Logging</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>An IDS Or IPS Is Deployed</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 11.4 <li>PCI DSS Requirement 11.4.a <li>PCI DSS Requirement 11.4.b <li>PCI DSS Requirement 11.4.c</li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>An Intrusion Detection System (IDS) or an Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) should be deployed.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>An Intrusion Detection System (IDS) or an Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) may detect an attack in real-time. The difference between IDS and IPS is that IPS not only detects an attack, but may also take some action.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Interview the responsible&amp;nbsp;staff to locate the IDS or the IPS. Ask them to demonstrate the administration interface and the logs. Verify that all traffic in the cardholder data environment is being monitored by examining the administration interface and the logs. Examine the configuration to verify that an alert is sent to&amp;nbsp;staff in the event of a suspected compromise. Refer to the vendor's documentation or technical support for instructions on how to configure the IDS or the IPS for maximum protection. Examine the configuration to make sure that the vendor's guidelines have been followed.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Choose an IDS or IPS solution. Deploy your chosen IDS or IPS. Configure the IDS or IPS to monitor all network traffic in the cardholder data environment by following the vendor's instructions. Configure the IDS or IPS to alert the staff in the event of a suspected compromise. Get the documentation from the vendor and use it to configure, maintain, and update the IDS or IPS.</p>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For a list of many IDS solutions, please see "Security Wizardry - Network IDS" at <a href="http://www.securitywizardry.com/index.php/products/IDS-and-IPS/Network-IDS.html">http://www.securitywizardry.com/index.php/products/IDS-and-IPS/Network-IDS.html</a>. <li>For information about Juniper IDS products, please see "IDP Series" at <a href="http://www.juniper.net/us/en/products-services/security/idp-series/">http://www.juniper.net/us/en/products-services/security/idp-series/</a>. <li>For information about NIKSUN NetDetector, please see "NIKSUN NetDetector" at <a href="http://www.niksun.com/product.php?id=4">http://www.niksun.com/product.php?id=4</a>. <li>For information about Trend Micro Deep Security, please see "Trend Micro Deep Security" at <a href="http://us.trendmicro.com/us/solutions/enterprise/security-solutions/virtualization/deep-security/index.html">http://us.trendmicro.com/us/solutions/enterprise/security-solutions/virtualization/deep-security/index.html</a>.</li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/f114910a-d391-4da1-a2eb-ab01306c4da8">Deploy an IDS or IPS</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>