<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1541355735" Content_Hash="1362506756">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>b0566722-81cc-4cd6-8357-ae0663fc84e7</Id>
    <Id_History>e1f53312-5ee2-4163-bfca-43b85e2c94b2,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>Access Control Systems Should Cover All System Components</Title>
    <Category>Configuration</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Access Control Systems Should Cover All System Components</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 7.2.1 <li>PCI DSS Requirement 7.2.3</li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Access control systems should cover all system components.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Using access control systems to secure all system components ensures that there is no information that can be retrieved by unauthorized personnel.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Identify all computers and other system components. Examine each system component to make sure it implements an access control system and that the access control systems are properly configured with a &amp;#8220;deny-all&amp;#8221; default setting.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Identify all computers and other system components.&amp;nbsp;Examine each system component to make sure it implements an access control system. Most modern Operating Systems and network devices implement access control. If a system component does not implement access control, it cannot be used within PCI DSS scope. Set a "deny-all" default on all access control systems.&amp;nbsp;Examine the access authorization documents in the network documentation. Implement the access privileges defined in the access authorization documents. The access authorization documents only allow data access that is required for each employee's job function, so they comply with the "least-privilege" principle.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/8c595f9b-18d8-4a21-8eb7-f822461578cf">Configure the Windows Access Control System</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>