<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="1158047509" Content_Hash="-385611995">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>b479019a-42d0-4cb3-96b2-3dcbf084441c</Id>
    <Id_History>ce687f01-50bd-44b5-b535-05616483727e,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c037d0d2-0617-44f3-b846-21dc3d02c4f8</Library_Id>
    <Title>All Users Have Unique User IDs</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>All Users Have Unique User IDs</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 8.1</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Each user should have a unique user account.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Giving each user a unique account allows managing access control effectively.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Use the following steps to check if all authorized users have unique user IDs:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Make a list of authorized users.</strong> Review the authorization forms in the network documentation and make a list of authorized users. </p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Make&amp;nbsp;a list of user accounts.</strong> Use the user management application to review user accounts. Make a list of accounts. In a Microsoft Active Directory environment, the user management application can be launched by clicking on "Start", "Programs", "Administrative Tools", "Active Directory Users and Computers".</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Compare the list of authorized users to the list of user accounts.</strong> Identify the user corresponding to each account to make sure the user exists and uses the account. Make sure that all the authorized users have accounts.</p>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Perform the following actions to make a new user account for each authorized user that does not have one in a Microsoft Active Directory environment:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Launch the user management console.</strong> Launch the the user management application by clicking on "Start", "Programs", "Administrative Tools", "Active Directory Users and Computers". </p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Create a new user account.</strong> To create a new user, navigate to the user list, right click on it, select "New", "User"</p>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Configure the new user account.</strong> Fill in the user account information in the "New Object - User" dialog. Configure group membership and data access control permissions for the new user account. Peform other actions associated with creating new user accounts, such as adding e-mail accounts, allocating personal work-space, etc.</p>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/d10d415c-d1b8-4dc4-8ad3-77ce8c9490a5">Formulate the User Authentication and Password Policies</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/fc992c4a-0866-4c4c-878a-98385e7b834c">Shared accounts are not used</a>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>