<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-223389838" Content_Hash="-2020520150">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>baaefcb2-f156-43bb-a3cd-e38a45b140e0</Id>
    <Id_History>059d8885-8c64-426e-9851-33be78b61587,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>c4b9cb6a-4561-4451-9b6c-4e59d73584f6</Library_Id>
    <Title>Cardholder Data Is Periodically Removed</Title>
    <Category>Sensitive Data</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Cardholder Data Is Periodically Removed</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author>Serge Batchilo, Jason Taylor, Joe Basirico</Author>
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>PCI DSS Requirement 3.1.d</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>The old cardholder data should be reviewed and the data that exceeds the stated business retention requirements should be erased at least every three months by an automated application or designated staff. The information security policy should include this requirement as well as the procedures for removing the outdated cardholder data.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Only the data that is necessary for business operations should be stored to limit the potential damage caused by a successful attack.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>Check the information security policy to make sure it includes this requirement and the procedures for removing all outdated cardholder data. Interview the responsible staff to make sure the procedures are implemented as stated.</p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>Identify the data retention requirements. Identify whether it is more practical to implement an automated application for removing the outdated data. Install and configure an application or script to remove the outdated cardholder data periodically or designate staff members to be responsible for periodically cleaning out the outdated data. Document the procedures for removing the outdated data. Include the requirement and the procedures for removing the old cardholder data in the information security policy.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <p>
        <a href="/article/d74a788a-2b59-4dff-b5ca-ab65eba6cd49">Prepare the Data Retention and Disposal Policies</a>
      </p>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>