<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1990397028" Content_Hash="-1152421162">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>d8c76643-3d59-4de6-8f05-68b29494a2ff</Id>
    <Id_History>1030f13a-fa23-4a50-b24d-5c6ba5b97845,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>A New Or Blank Session ID Is Assigned on Logout</Title>
    <Category>Session Management</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>A New Or Blank Session ID Is Assigned on Logout</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies To</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>ASP.NET 4.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Verify that a new or blank session ID is assigned on logout.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Reset the session ID of the user upon logout to prevent people using the same computer from being able to retrieve the session ID after the user has logged out.</p>
  <h1>How To Check</h1>
  <p>To verify that a new or blank session ID is assigned on logout:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify logout functionality.</strong> Find the function or functions that are called to log the user out.</p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Verify that the session state is cleared on logout. </strong>Review the logout function to make sure it clears the session state on the server by using code such as the following:</p>
        <pre>Session.Abandon();</pre>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Verify that the session ID cookie is reset.</strong> Review the logout function to make sure it resets the session ID cookie by using code such as the following:</p>
          <pre>Response.Cookies.Add(new HttpCookie("ASP.NET_SessionId", ""));</pre>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h1>How To Fix</h1>
  <p>To assign a blank session ID on logout:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Identify logout functionality.</strong> Find the function or functions that are called to log the user out.</p>
      <li>
        <p>
          <strong>Clear the session state on logout.</strong> Add the following code to the logout function to clear the session state on the server:</p>
        <pre>Session.Abandon();</pre>
        <li>
          <p>
            <strong>Reset the session ID cookie.</strong> Add the following code to the logout function to set the session ID to null:</p>
          <pre>Response.Cookies.Add(new HttpCookie("ASP.NET_SessionId", ""));</pre>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ol>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>