<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-814931439" Content_Hash="-495089872">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>66b69d12-599c-4116-b3c6-0c1d3bea1d2d</Id>
    <Id_History>3cc1762e-4c53-48af-9f9d-bb775e8a39fb,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>How to Prevent SQL Injection Attacks</Title>
    <Category>Data Access</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>How To</Type>
    <DirectLink>How to Prevent SQL Injection Attacks</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Blaine Wastell, Prashant Bansode, Chaitanya Bijwe</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Description</h1>
  <p>To help prevent SQL injection attacks, start by thoroughly validating and constraining input. Validate input for type, length, format, and range. Use regular expressions to validate text input. Also use parameterized stored procedures for data access. This ensures that input values are checked for type and length. Parameters are also treated as safe literal values and not as executable code within the database. Avoid stored procedures that accept a single parameter that has the query to execute. Instead, pass query parameters only. If you cannot use stored procedures, use SQL statements with parameters and do not build SQL statements by concatenating input values with SQL commands. </p>
  <p>Use structured exception handling to catch exceptions when your code accesses the database, and make sure that you do not return exception details to the client. As an additional precaution, make sure that the account your application uses to connect to the database has restricted permissions in the database.</p>
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>