<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="379466460" Content_Hash="-1542613511">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>f16917ba-339b-4f71-84c9-cc03bdabab53</Id>
    <Id_History>cc943274-2062-40d0-85bb-63800e082546,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>ea854894-8e16-46c8-9c61-737ef46d7e82</Library_Id>
    <Title>How to Obfuscate Your Assembly</Title>
    <Category>Obfuscation</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET 2.0</Technology>
    <Type>How To</Type>
    <DirectLink>How to Obfuscate Your Assembly</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>J.D. Meier, Alex Mackman, Blaine Wastell, Prashant Bansode, Chaitanya Bijwe</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies to</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>.NET 2.0</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Description</h1>
  <p>To obfuscate your assemblies you can use Dotfuscator Community Edition which is included with Visual Studio.&amp;nbsp;2005. Ensure that you have a mechanism to deal with exception messages and stack traces from the obfuscated assembly because these are also obfuscated. You can use the map file generated by Dotfuscator which has the mapping between the old and the new symbol names. You can also use the Lucidator tool that is supplied with the standard and professional versions of Dotfuscator for this purpose. </p>
  <p>Use declarative obfuscation to specify obfuscation parameters in code for more fine-grained control. The .NET Framework version 2.0 has two new custom attributes, which aid Dotfuscator while obfuscating assemblies: <b>System.Reflection.ObfuscateAssemblyAttribute</b> and <b>System.Reflection.ObfuscationAttribute</b>. Use <b>System.Reflection.ObfuscateAssemblyAttribute</b> to specify assembly-level obfuscation attributes and <b>System.Reflection.ObfuscationAttribute</b> to specify member-level obfuscation settings. </p>
  <p>Use the member-level attribute to control which members should be obfuscated. Make sure that you obfuscate shared assemblies by specifying library mode to ensure that public entry points are not obfuscated. You can do this either by using <b>ObfuscateAssemblyAttribute</b> or by setting the appropriate configuration in the Dotfuscator tool. </p>
  <br />
  <hr />
  <p>Adapted from Microsoft patterns &amp; practices guidance.</p>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>