<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="630402816" Content_Hash="-591720415">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>8cc6c40a-5a4c-4d77-8900-4b896e2d3912</Id>
    <Id_History>8cc6c40a-5a4c-4d77-8900-4b896e2d3912,c9c8b3ce-cdc9-4b18-9c1a-e8afb9784219,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>JSF Encode Untrusted Data in Output</Title>
    <Category>Encoding</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Java</Technology>
    <Type>Code Example</Type>
    <DirectLink>Use H:outputText to Encode Echoed Input in JSF</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="markdown">
    <Data><![CDATA[## Applies To ##

- JSF (Java Server Faces).


## Summary ##

Use h:outputText to encode output for display in the HTML entity context. This provides protection from XSS attacks. The h:outputText tag HTML entity encodes the <, >, and & characters. This prevents XSS in the HTML entity context and ensures dynamic input does not result in executable code when presented to a user.

Using h:outputText is appropriate in the HTML Entity context. However, it should not be used in other contexts (such as CSS, URL, etc.) due to the limited number of characters it encodes, as well as the HTML entity specific encoding mechanism. The h:outputText tag should be used when data is displayed in view mode (non-editable) in the HTML entity context.


## Problem Example ##

The use of h:outputText is improper in these examples due to the inappropriate context or configuration. See the examples below:

    <a href="<h:outputText value="#{myobj.myvar}"/>">Some Website</a>

Use of tag in the URL context - HTML entity encoding is not sufficient in this context.

or

    <h:outputText value="#{myobj.myvar}" escape="false" />

Use of escape="false" prevents encoding - overrides the default, which is true.


## Solution Example ##

The use of h:outputText is appropriate in these examples due to the inappropriate context or configuration. See the examples below:

    <div class="container">
      <h:outputText value="#{param.name}"/>
    </div>

or

    <h:outputText value="#{myobj.myvar}"/>

or

    <h:outputText value="#{myobj.myvar}" escape="true"/>

Use of escape="true" - ensures encoding occurs - true is the default.


## Guideline ##

* [Encode Untrusted Data in Output](9b0ef1a5-c143-4e64-81cc-9e02ccbd9fbd)]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>