<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>0be51dfa-986a-402d-b446-b966d16a307d</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Design Reviews Are Performed for Cloud Deployments</Title>
    <Category>Security Engineering</Category>
    <Phase>Design</Phase>
    <Technology>AWS</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="markdown">
    <Data><![CDATA[##What to Check For##

Verify that design reviews are performed for cloud deployments.

##Why##

A design review will identify exposure to newly-discovered vulnerabilities, and maintain the overall security posture for cloud deployments.

Reviews provide checkpoints to ensure continuing compliance with accrediting authorities. When a design review identifies areas of concern, rather than working through future security incidents, it is more effective to fix and re-deploy in the present.


##When##

Apply design reviews iteratively throughout deployment. When your design evolves, it is also necessary to thoroughly check architecture and source code for potential exposure to threats. Also review configuration changes for adherence with security management policy and guidelines.

##How to Check##

To verify that design reviews are performed for cloud deployments:

1. **Identify responsible personnel.** Find and interview employees responsible for performing design reviews for cloud deployments.

2. **Examine design review results.** Review the results of the previously conducted design reviews and assess their quality.


##How to Fix##

Use a question-driven approach to expose the highest risk design concerns, and use the security frame to dive into areas that reveal common mistakes. The following steps can guide your approach when reviewing the cloud deployment.

1. **Deployment and infrastructure.** Review the design of your application in relation to the target deployment environment and the associated security policies. Consider the restrictions imposed by the underlying infrastructure layer security.

2. **Security frame.** Review the approach to critical areas in your application, including authentication, authorization, input / data validation, exception management, and other areas. Use the application vulnerability categories as a roadmap and back-check, so that you do not overlook any flags during the review.

3. **Tier-by-tier analysis.** Walk through the logical tiers of your application, and evaluate security choices within your presentation, business, and data access layers.

4. **Record design review results.** Use a standard checklist and customize it for your unique application architecture. Walk through the prescribed review checks consistently, being sure to verify that previous assumptions are still valid for current business case and security. Record your findings, and initiate cloud deployment (application and architecture) update requests in accordance with change management policy and procedure.


]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>