<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>188b7c2c-cee0-4e41-874e-6c20c4c845e2</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Configure ACLs for S3 Objects</Title>
    <Category>System Hardening</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology>AWS</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="markdown">
    <Data><![CDATA[##Applies To##

- Amazon Web Services (AWS)


##What to Do##

Configure Access Control Lists (ACLs) for Amazon S3 resources, such as objects and buckets, to enforce your security management plan.

Management and configuration of ACLs for S3 objects can be performed by:

- Managing ACLs with AWS Management Console
- Managing ACLs with AWS SDK for Java
- Managing ACLs with AWS SDK for .NET
- Managing ACLs with REST API.


##Why##

When the ACL for an S3 object is properly configured, AWS accounts or groups you specify become grantees with permissions on the object. Amazon S3 verifies that object requests are permissible for these requesters. If the ACL is misconfigured, these requests will fail.


##When##

When Amazon S3 creates a bucket or object at your request, a default ACL is also created for the account owner, who now owns the resource. The default ACL grants the account owner full control. This is shown in the sample bucket ACL. To allow other AWS accounts and groups access to this resource, the ACLs must be further configured. The structure of the ACL can be found in Access Control List (ACL) Overview topic in the [Amazon Simple Storage Service Developer Guide](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service: Developer Guide").

Note that ACLs are ***not used*** with your AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) users. You cannot grant permissions with an ACL to your IAM users. For that purpose, use the IAM console to set permissions for the users. Refer to the [Amazon Simple Storage Service Console User Guide](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/UG/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service Console User Guide") for further explanation.


##How##

To configure Amazon S3 ACLs with the simplest method, use the AWS Management Console. AWS SDK (for Java and .NET) and API methods and operations are introduced here for information purpose.

###Use AWS Management Console###

1. **Login to Management Console.** Sign in to the [AWS S3 Management Console](https://console.aws.amazon.com/s3/ "AWS S3 Management Console"). 

2. **Add Permissions.** Select the target bucket or object in the left pane. Access the properties and view permissions already set. Add more permissions to this ACL, and use a pre-defined group for the grantee, or type in an AWS canonical user name. Check the box to use appropriate permissions for the application. A checked box means the permission is in effect. Note that the labels on the console screen relate to actual ACL permission names as follows:
 - List (READ) 
 - Upload/Delete (WRITE)
 - View Permissions (READ_ACP)
 - Edit Permissions (WRITE_ACP).

3. **Change Permissions.** To change permissions, scroll through the rows of permissions that have been established for the application. Select or de-select each permission as required, and apply the changes.

###Use AWS SDK for Java###

With AWS SDK for Java, you can create a resource and grant permissions programmatically. These functions are provided in code:

 - AccessControlList is added to a request.
 - Grantee and permissions are stated.
 - PutObject request specifies permissions to accounts and/or predefined groups (such as AllUsers).

Detailed examples and additional methods for using the AWS SDK for Java can be found in the [Amazon Simple Storage Service Developer Guide](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service: Developer Guide"). Code is available to modify the ACL on existing buckets and objects, and use predefined ACLs with groups.


###Use AWS SDK for .NET###

The AWS SDK for .NET can be used to change permissions on an existing resource with C#.

 - Call the AmazonS3Client.PutACL method.
 - Create an instance of S3AccessControlList class with a list of ACL grants.
 - Add new grants.
 - Send a PutACL request.

Detailed examples and additional methods for using the AWS SDK for .NET can be found in the [Amazon Simple Storage Service Developer Guide](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service: Developer Guide"). Code is available for setting an ACL when creating a resource, and for using predefined ACLs with groups.


###Use REST API###

REST API support for configuring ACLs is available with the operations listed below. Discussion of the API is beyond the scope of this guideline.

For information on AWS REST API support, refer to the following topics in the [Amazon Simple Storage Service API Reference](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/API/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service API Reference").

- GET Bucket acl
- PUT Bucket acl
- GET Object acl
- PUT Object acl
- PUT Object
- PUT Bucket
- PUT Object Copy
- Initiate Multipart Upload


##Additional Resources##

- "Operations on Buckets" and "Operations on Objects" sections of [Amazon Simple Storage Service API Reference](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/API/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service API Reference")
- "Editing Bucket Permissions" and "Editing Object Permissions" sections of [Amazon Simple Storage Service Console User Guide](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/UG/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service Console User Guide")
- "Managing Access Permissions" section of [Amazon Simple Storage Service Developer Guide](http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/ "Amazon Simple Storage Service: Developer Guide")
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>