<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1972f5be-2a76-4e26-beb4-2fd5eaf37f49</Id>
    <Id_History>9ea85350-3621-41b5-8ccb-d5480e0c2019,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>d9c2b53f-5b05-4152-be72-e79d72854707</Library_Id>
    <Title>Conduct a Security Deployment Review</Title>
    <Category>Security Engineering</Category>
    <Phase>Deployment</Phase>
    <Technology>Any</Technology>
    <Type>Guideline</Type>
    <DirectLink>Conduct a Security Deployment Review</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Do</h1>
  <p>When you deploy your application, perform a security deployment review to identify potential security vulnerabilities introduced by inappropriate configuration settings. <br /></p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>A security deployment review helps ensure 
that configuration and deployment problems are discovered before they result in an application vulnerability. Even the most securely 
designed and implemented application can be compromised by an error 
during deployment, leaving it open to attack.</p>
  <h1>When</h1>
  <p>Perform the security deployment review during the deployment stage in the application development life cycle.</p>
  <h1>How</h1>
  <p>Use the following techniques when conducting a deployment review:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Use server security categories (and application security categories, when applicable).</strong>&amp;nbsp;Use server security categories (and application security categories, when applicable) to help make deployment reviews for security systematic and repeatable.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Break down your deployment review.</strong>&amp;nbsp;You can use the categories to break down your application deployment for further analysis and to help identify vulnerabilities.</p>
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>
        <strong>Review systematically.</strong>&amp;nbsp;By using categories, you can systematically go through the deployment review process from start to finish or pick a particular category for further analysis.</p>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h2>
  </h2>
  <h3>
    <i>Server Security Categories</i>
  </h3>
  <p>Patterns &amp; practices security guidance includes server security categories for each major application type. Use these categories as a starting point and add new items as you learn more about deployment reviews. The below list shows the categories that are common to most deployed applications.</p>
  <ol style="margin: 10px 0px 10px 25px; padding: 0px 0px 0px 30px; color: rgb(17, 17, 17); font-family: 'Segoe UI', 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif; font-size: small;">
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Patches and Updates.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Patches and updates fix known vulnerabilities with relatively little effort, so installing them is a good first step.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Accounts.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Only grant access that is required for users to perform their job functions. Remove accounts that are not used. Disable accounts that have been idle for a long time. Require strong passwords and password changes to fend off password-guessing attacks. Log authentication failure. Notify the users of attacks on their accounts.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Auditing and Logging.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Logging is one of the most useful tools for becoming aware of attacks and for investigating attacks that have already occurred. Enable and configure logging. Ideally, logs should be sent to a centralized log server where they are monitored in real time or audited daily.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Files and Directories.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Configure access controls to only allow authorized users and services to access data. Access controls should be configured with "deny-all" defaults. Log unauthorized data access events.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Ports.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Open ports accept incoming connections over the network. This makes them a simple attack vector. Scan your server for open ports to make sure that no insecure or unnecessary services are&amp;nbsp; running on your server.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Protocols.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Some protocols have been designed without security in mind. Avoid using protocols that are known to have security vulnerabilities, such as Telnet, which transmits authentication credentials in plain-text. If such protocols are necessary for operations, use a secure alternative like SSH or make use of additional security technologies, such as VPN, to provide secure communications and authentication.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Registry.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Secure configuration settings stored in the registry by using ACLs and by disabling the remote registry service.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Services.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Disable unused services. Secure, configure, and monitor important services. If a service such as NFS must be prohibited from entering or leaving a protected subnet. Either disable it, or consider using a secure alternative or using additional security technologies like a firewall to block it.</p>
    </li>
    <li style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">
      <p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 1em; padding: 0px; line-height: 1.5em;">
        <strong style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Shares.</strong>&amp;nbsp;Protect file shares with access controls. Allow only the minimum required amount of access to the smallest necessary set of data. Remove any unused file shares.</p>
    </li>
  </ol>
  <h3>
    <i>Application Security Categories</i>
  </h3>
  <p>Application security categories are different for different applications. Some application types will require review of application security categories as well as server security categories. For example, you should review application-level&amp;nbsp;<i>application.conf</i>&amp;nbsp;file content that configures settings for Scala applications as well as the <i>routes</i>&amp;nbsp;file that manages routing in Scala applications. Use server security categories like the conf file as a starting point, and add new items as you learn more about deployment reviews.</p>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For more information, see “patterns &amp; practices Security Deployment Review Index” at&amp;nbsp;<a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff648510.aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff648510.aspx</a></li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>