<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>765a310c-8371-43f2-adbe-ff117d2d319c</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Use Load Balancing</Title>
    <Category />
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Technology Independent</Technology>
    <Type />
    <DirectLink />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="markdown">
    <Data><![CDATA[##What to Do##

Implement load balancing by reviewing currently-available products and techniques. Choose a solution that satisfies business case. Use performance metrics to gauge the effectiveness of load balancing.


##Why##

Load balancing is usually used for performance reasons and to mitigate Denial-of-Service attacks.


##How##

Begin with these steps for a secure load-balancing implementation.

1. **Review available load-balancing options.** Make a list of load-balancing products, and determine what features are provided, such as: request routing, URL rewriting and redirecting, health checks, and auto scaling.

2. **Choose load-balancing solution.** One solution may not provide the necessary features for your application. For example, URL rewriting and redirecting may be built-in, but auto scaling is missing. You may need to integrate different products in order to implement 100% of your security design features.

3. **Configure load-balancing solution.** Use the vendor's instruction to setup the load balancing solution.

4. **Test load balancing solution.** Before going live, test the load balancer. Use the vendor's instructions, if available, or contact them for information on how to test their solution.

5. **Make adjustments to configuration.**  If any issues are discovered, correct them before deploying the solution.

6. **Monitor performance.** Use the vendor-provided tools to monitor load-balancing performance.
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>