<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>88d0284b-13ab-4469-9614-f053a0822ae4</Id>
    <Id_History>a4476415-743c-480b-b618-28d37ba9a573,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>d9c2b53f-5b05-4152-be72-e79d72854707</Library_Id>
    <Title>Penetration Testing Is Performed</Title>
    <Category>Security Engineering</Category>
    <Phase>Test</Phase>
    <Technology>Any</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>Penetration Testing Is Performed</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>What to Check For</h1>
  <p>Penetration testing results should be documented and the identified vulnerabilities should be fixed.</p>
  <h1>Why</h1>
  <p>Penetration testing helps discover vulnerabilities before someone else does.</p>
  <h1>How to Check</h1>
  <p>
    Check project documentation for information about penetration testing to make sure that penetration testing has been performed. Documentation should include penetration testing results, and verification that identified vulnerabilities were fixed. <br /></p>
  <p>
    <b>Note</b>&amp;nbsp; There are many different penetration testing methodologies and procedures, depending on specific aspects of the application or system being tested. One thing is common to all penetration tests - they should be documented. <br /></p>
  <h1>How to Fix</h1>
  <p>If penetration testing has not been performed, perform the testing. One option is to contract an information security consulting company to perform the penetration testing. The methodology&amp;nbsp;for carrying out penetration tests involves examining the application environment for common vulnerabilities, using automated tools to search for low hanging fruit, then manually checking the application for the most dangerous and common vulnerability types and attack vectors.</p>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="6fb4fe36-39a5-424d-8012-d751d2441069">Perform Penetration Testing</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="24b05535-fc76-4b18-aba2-9f14b3ecfd88">Create a Threat Mode</a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>