<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>a03f6c47-68e9-4c90-baeb-cae5b1e24fc4</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Check Authorization for System Resource Access</Title>
    <Category />
    <Phase />
    <Technology />
    <Type />
    <DirectLink />
    <Tag />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="markdown">
    <Data><![CDATA[##Check Authorization for System Resource Access##


##Applies To##

- Ruby


##What to Do##

Check authorization before accessing system resources such as files, database connections, and network sockets.


##Why##

Access to system resources, such as files, must be considered by the developer. The application should check if the user is authorized to access system objects.

If the application exposes a system resource to the wrong control sphere, there is inappropriate access to the resource (CWE-668).


##When##

The application should always check if a file or other system resource should be available to the user.


##How##

Outline for "Check Authorization for Access to System Resources"

1. **Identify all operations performed by the application.** Make a spreadsheet that lists all operations implemented by the application.
2. **Identify system resources used by the application.** For each operation, determine what files, database connections, network sockets, or other system objects that are subject to access controls are being used. Add this information to the spreadsheet.
3. **Find code that accesses system resources.** Find all code that accesses system resources. Add information about this code to the spreadsheet.
4. **Check authorization before accessing system resources.** Add code that checks authorization to each function that accesses system resources before performing access to system resources. Use reference maps to restrict access to explicitly-authorized resources if possible.


##Additional Resources##

- [CWE-285: Improper Authorization)](https://cwe.mitre.org/ "CWE-285: Improper Authorization")
- [CWE-668: Exposure of Resource to Wrong Sphere](https://cwe.mitre.org/ "CWE-668: Exposure of Resource to Wrong Sphere")]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>