<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>b9993720-8486-4e03-adf9-c6645cf7e374</Id>
    <Id_History>1513a133-0a53-46b5-b0b1-79b6dcb52ca2,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>7d2d0571-e542-45cd-9335-d7a0556c2bea</Library_Id>
    <Title>All Password Fields Are Masked</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Web Application</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>All Password Fields Are Masked</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Applies To==

* Web Applications

==What to Check For==

Verify that all password fields are masked. Masking means displaying identical characters when user enters input. When a user enters a password "password", the masked field may look like "********".

==Why==

Masking password fields helps protect user passwords from someone that may be looking at their screen. The practice of looking at someone's screen to see secret information is known as "shoulder-surfing".

==How to Check==

To verify that all password fields are masked:

# **Identify all password fields in the application.** Review all the pages in the application to find all password-type fields. Password-type fields include secret answers, CVV, PIN, and other data, which is equivalent to passwords.
# **Verify that password fields are masked.** View each page that contains a password input field in a browser and verify that each password input field is masked.

==How to Fix==

To mask all password fields:

# **Identify all password-type fields in the application.** Review all the pages in the application to find all password-type fields. Password-type fields include secret answers, CVV, PIN, and other data, which is equivalent to passwords.
# **Use password fields that mask user input.** Masking password fields is usually done by using a "password" type HTML input field, like so: {{{ <form> }}} \\ {{{ ... }}} \\ {{{ <input type="password" name="pass" AUTOCOMPLETE="off"/> }}} \\ {{{ ... }}} \\ {{{ </form> }}} \\ Please, note that the autocomplete property is set to "off" - this prevents the browser from remembering the password in its autocomplete list. Preventing the browser from storing passwords in the autocomplete list protects the passwords from being compromised if the user's operating system is compromised.
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>