<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>ba5a7df0-f96f-4f39-9429-fbd566d7fd6b</Id>
    <Id_History>ba5a7df0-f96f-4f39-9429-fbd566d7fd6b,1576f6bb-cbac-491e-9b9b-ddc880c81662,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>WS-Routing Is Not Used</Title>
    <Category>Communication Security</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>.NET</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>WS-Routing Is Not Used</DirectLink>
    <Tag>ASP.NET,ASP.NET 4.0,ASP</Tag>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Applies To==

* ASP.NET 4.0

==What to Check For==

Verify that WS-Routing is not used.

==Why==

Don't use WS-Routing, because WS-Routing is vulnerable to routing detour attacks. The WS-Routing protocol doesn't have sufficient security features, so it should be avoided. 

==How to Check==

To check whether WS-Routing is used, ask developers whether the application actually uses WS-Routing, and review application code to find code that uses WS-Routing.  Search for keywords like "WS-Routing" and "r:path" to help find code that uses WS-Routing. 

If WS-Routing is used, the code that uses it should be either removed or changed to use WS-Addressing instead.

==How to Fix==

To avoid using WS-Routing:

# **Find code that uses WS-Routing.** Ask developers whether the application actually uses WS-Routing. Review application code to find code that uses WS-Routing.
# **Determine whether SOAP message routing functionality is needed.** Most real-life applications that use Web Services can be implemented without using SOAP message routing. Review application requirements to determine whether SOAP message routing is necessary.
# **Remove or replace code that uses WS-Routing.** If SOAP message routing is not necessary, then remove the code that uses it. If SOAP message routing is necessary, rewrite code that uses WS-Routing to use WS-Addressing instead.
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>