<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>c24e2edb-e72a-4de7-979e-f4f852c795fd</Id>
    <Id_History>7d230709-ff48-4e61-a8bf-e6f81005f307,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>7d2d0571-e542-45cd-9335-d7a0556c2bea</Library_Id>
    <Title>All Access Is Denied by Default</Title>
    <Category>Authorization</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Web Application</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink>All Access Is Denied by Default</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Applies To==

* Web Applications

==What to Check For==

Check that all access is denied by default in web server settings and in authorization code.

==Why==

Denying all access by default assures that only explicitly authorized access is possible.

==How to Check==

To make sure all access is denied by default:

# **Enumerate all sensitive pages.** Make a list of all pages that handle sensitive or private information.
# **Verify that all access is denied by default on the web server.** Examine the web server configuration to make sure that all access is denied by default unless explicitly authorized.
# **Verify that all access is denied by default in authorization code.** Review your application's authorization code to make sure that all access is denied by default.

==How to Fix==

To deny all access by default:

# **Enumerate all sensitive pages.** Make a list of all pages that handle sensitive or private information.
# **Configure web-server authorization.** Configure the web-server to deny all access by default for all locations that contain sensitive pages or data. The exact procedures are different for different web servers - please, refer to your web server's documentation for detailed instructions on configuring its access control settings.
# **Deny all access by default in your authorization code.** Implement authorization in your application to deny all access by default.]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>