<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>fd15d30d-8132-48fc-8962-870f096eff3b</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6234f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Particularly Sensitive Cardholder Data Is Not Stored</Title>
    <Category>Cryptography</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Technology Independent</Technology>
    <Type>Checklist Item</Type>
    <DirectLink />
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==What to Check For==

Verify that PINs, verification codes, and full track contents are not stored.

==Why==

One of the most prized assets that attackers are after is cardholder data that can be used for fraud. Do not store PINs, verification codes, or full track contents to prevent this data from becoming available to attackers even if the system is completely compromised.

==How to Check==

To verify that PINs, verification codes, and full track contents are not stored:

# **Identify code that handles PINs, verification codes, and full track contents.** Make a spreadsheet of all the code that handles PINs, verification codes and full track contents.
# **Examine code that handles particularly sensitive cardholder data.** Examine each piece of code that handles PINs, verification codes and full track contents to make sure that such information is never stored.

==How to Fix==

To avoid storing PINs, verification codes, or full track contents:

# **Identify code that handles PINs, verification codes, and full track contents.** Make a spreadsheet of all the code that handles PINs, verification codes and full track contents.
# **Examine code that handles particularly sensitive cardholder data.** Examine each piece of code that handles PINs, verification codes and full track contents to make sure that such information is never stored.
# **Remove code that stores PINs, verification codes, or full track contents.** If there is code that stores such sensitive information, remove it.]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>